<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<event_data>
	<event>
		<name>Viral Video Contest</name>
		<file_name>viral_video</file_name>
		<subject>Cultural_NOT</subject>
		<oneline_desc><![CDATA[Stand-up comedy, short movies, music videos, parodies or parodies of parodies&mdash;do whatever it takes to float the YouTube boat and go viral!]]></oneline_desc>
		<desc>
			<para>
				It's time to take out your video cameras and get filming!
			</para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[Stand-up comedy, short movies, music videos, moments of serendipity, cute kittens, parodies or parodies of parodies&mdash;do whatever it takes to float the YouTube boat.]]>
			</para>
			<para>
				There are no restrictions: creativity is the only guide as you compete to become the next YouTube sensation.
			</para>
			<para><![CDATA[<b>Prizes worth Rs. 5000 at stake!</b>]]></para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[ <CENTER> <b> Co-ordinator: </b> <br>Madhwesh C. R.<br> <a href="mailto:madhwesh@pravega.org" target="_blank">madhwesh@pravega.org</a></CENTER>]]>
			</para>	
		</desc>
		<image>crypto.png</image>
		<rules_list>
			<rule><![CDATA[Videos must be of minimum resolution: 640&times;480]]></rule>
			<rule>Video cannot exceed 12 minutes.</rule>
			<rule>The video must be uploaded newly onto YouTube through your own channel. The description to your video must mention it as an entry to the contest and should carry back a link to the Pravega homepage.</rule>
			<rule>There can be a maximum of five members in a team.</rule>
			<rule><![CDATA[After uploading, you must send the video URL with your team details to <a href="mailto:madhwesh@pravega.org" target="_blank">madhwesh@pravega.org</a>]]></rule>
			<rule>The videos will be evaluated and prizes awarded based on a combination of online popularity and invited judges' opinion.</rule>
			<rule>The judges' decision is final and binding.</rule>
		</rules_list>
	</event>
	
	<event>
		<name>Wordsmithy</name>
		<file_name>wordsmithy</file_name>
		<image>events/wordsmithy.jpg</image>
		<subject>Cultural</subject>
		<oneline_desc>What ho, budding Wordsmiths! Are you up for some essay-crafting?</oneline_desc>
		<desc>
			<para>
				Pravega invites all budding wordsmiths to craft essays on any of our six topics.
			</para>
			
			<para>
				<![CDATA[<CENTER><b><a href="rulebook/Wordsmithy.pdf">Essay topics are out. Click here to download!</a></b></CENTER>]]>
			</para>

			<para>
				Wordsmithy is all about putting across <i>your</i> ideas in a persuasive and coherent way; we do not really care about how well you dodge split infinitives or if
				<![CDATA[<a target="_blank" href="http://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/sesquipedalian#Noun">sesquipedalian</a>]]> blood runs in your veins. Feel free to use any kind of persuasion in your essay: images, cartoons, sketches or even links to audio/video! But don't forget to keep <![CDATA[<a target="_blank" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chekhov's_gun">Mr. Chekhov</a>]]> in the back of your mind!
			</para>
				
			<para> </para>
				
			<para><![CDATA[ <CENTER><b>What's at stake?</b><br> 1st Prize: Rs. 3000<br> 2nd Prize: Rs. 2000<br> 3rd Prize: Rs. 1000<br>The top 10 essays will get certificates from IISc Pravega 2014.</CENTER>]]></para>
				
			<para>Wordsmithy winners are announced!</para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[
				Thank you for the overwhelming response. We had over 130 registrations!<br><br>
				<b>Senior Category:</b><br>
				1st Prize: Suvam Mukherjee, IISc, Bangalore<br>
				2nd Prize: Gaurav Somwanshi, IIM Lucknow<br>
				3rd Prize: Anusha S Rao, MCC, Bangalore<br><br>

				<b>Honorable Mentions:</b><br>
				Sreya Mallika Datta, Presidency College, Kolkata<br>
				Deblina Bhattacharya, Christ University, Bangalore<br>
				Harish S, Amrita University, Coimbatore<br>
				P Kalyani, KMC Mangalore<br>
				Sweta Akundi<br>
				Minal Sukumar, MCC, Bangalore<br>
				Dhathri N, UVCE, Bangalore<br><br>

				<b>Junior Category:</b><br>
				1st prize: Kasturi Pananjady, NPS Indiranagar, Bangalore.
				]]>
			</para>
			<para>Please email to coordinator to know how to obtain your prizes/certificates.</para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[ <CENTER> <b> Co-ordinator: </b> <br> Suhas M<br> <a href="mailto:suhas@pravega.org" target="_blank">suhas@pravega.org</a><br></CENTER>]]>
			</para>	
		</desc>
		<rules_list>
			<rule>There are two categories:<![CDATA[<br>1. <b>Junior</b>: Grade 12 and below.<br>2. <b>Senior</b>: Undergraduate and Postgraduate.<br>Topics remain same for both. Prizes will be awarded separately.<br>]]></rule>
			<rule><![CDATA[<b>Criteria for evaluation</b>:<br>Creativity: 50%<br>Structure and coherence: 20%<br>Adherence to topic: 10%<br>Language: 5%<br>'Wow' factor: 15%<br>]]></rule>
			<rule>Plagiarism of any sort will not be tolerated and essays with plagiarised content will be disqualified. We treat intellectual dishonesty very seriously!</rule>
			<rule>Content from any source must be cited before inclusion in your essay.</rule>
			<rule>The essay must be freshly written and must not be previously published in digital or print media.</rule>
			<rule>Word limit: 2000 words.</rule>
			<rule>You must register yourself for the competition on the website to participate.</rule>
			<rule>Email the essay in pdf/doc/rtf/docx format to the co-ordinator's email id: <![CDATA[<a href="suhas@pravega.org">suhas@pravega.org</a>]]></rule>
			<rule>The judges' decision is final and binding.</rule>
			<rule>Submission deadline: 11:59PM 25th January 2014</rule>
		</rules_list>
	</event>
	
	<event>
		<name><![CDATA[Carl Zeiss Pratik&#7771;ti]]></name>
		<file_name>pratikriti</file_name>
		<subject>Cultural</subject>
		<oneline_desc> Search for the ultimate shutterbug. How good are you at arresting time, immortalizing moments and photographing beauty lurking in the ordinary?</oneline_desc>
		<desc>
			<para>	
				<![CDATA[ <i>While there is perhaps a province in which the photograph can tell us nothing more than what we see with our own eyes, there is another in which it proves to us how little our eyes permit us to see.</i>]]>
				<![CDATA[<div align="right">&#x2015;Dorothea Lange</div>]]>
			</para>
			<para>
				Pravega is on the lookout for the ultimate shutterbug! How good are you at arresting time in its tracks, immortalizing moments and unraveling hidden beauties in the ordinary? Pratikriti is our theme based online photography competition, sponsored by Carl Zeiss. Please see the rules below for more details. Register now!
			</para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[<b>Theme:</b>  prak&#7771;ti ke ra&#7749;g/Colors of Nature]]>
			</para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[<center><b>The competition is over. Winners are announed!</b>
				<br>
				1st Prize: Abhinav Jain<br>
				2nd Prize: Akash Sonawane<br>
				3rd Prize: Kishore Ranganath R<br>
				<br><br>
				<b>Congratulations to the winners!</b></center>]]>
			</para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[ <CENTER> <b> Co-ordinator: </b> <br>Madhwesh C. R.<br> <a href="mailto:madhwesh@pravega.org" target="_blank">madhwesh@pravega.org</a></CENTER>]]>
			</para>	
		</desc>
		<image>porp.png</image>
		<rules_list>
			<rule>Theme for the photography contest is Prakriti ke rang/The colours of nature.</rule>
			<rule><![CDATA[Pratik&#7771;ti]]> is a single theme based competition.</rule>
			<rule>Participants need to register on pravega.org and for this event (the register button above).</rule>
			<rule>Applicants will have to send their entries (max 2 per person) to <![CDATA[<a href="mailto:photography@pravega.org" target="_blank">photography@pravega.org</a>]]>. Rename your photo to <![CDATA[&lt;Name&gt;-&lt;College&gt;-&lt;Pratikriti14&gt; and mail it to <a href="photography@pravega.org">photography@pravega.org</a>]]>. Example: If Rajesh from IISc Bangalore has to submit an entry the file name should be Rajesh-IIScBangalore-Pratikriti14.</rule>
			<rule>Shortlisted entries will be uploaded onto the Pravega Facebook Page</rule>
			<rule>Camera resolution should be at least 3.2 megapixels.</rule>
			<rule>Tagging "friends" on the entry is not allowed, in order to gain likes! You can "Share" the page and the entry for that.</rule>
			<rule>Posting offensive comments on opponent's entry is strictly NOT allowed. Otherwise action will be taken accordingly.</rule>
			<rule>Participants have time till 12 a.m., 24th January, 2014 (Friday) to get "Likes" on their entry.</rule>
			<rule>In photo editing only cropping and adjustment of hue/saturation; brightness/Contrast; levels are allowed. Photo-morphing, manipulations or local editing is not allowed.</rule>
			<rule>Do not include your credentials (name, address, watermarks etc.) in the picture or the frame. Such photos will not be considered for the contest.</rule>
			
			<rule><![CDATA[<b>Judging Criteria </b>
				<ul style="margin-left:25px;">
					<li>Judging will be done on the basis of basic rules of photography, composition, colours, creativity and aptness to the theme. The number of likes on the photo will carry a huge weightage in the final score. So the photos with more likes have higher chances of winning the competition.</li>
					<li>People need to like the Pravega page first, and then the entry of their choice. Otherwise that "Like" will not be considered.</li>
					<li>Result dates would be announced soon.</li>
					<li>Decision of the judges will be final and binding.</li>
				</ul>]]>
			</rule>
		</rules_list>	
	</event>

	<event>
		<name>Battle of Bands</name>
		<file_name>battle_of_bands</file_name>
		<subject>Cultural</subject>
		<oneline_desc>Pravega invites the best bands from across the nation for a head-on face-off.</oneline_desc>
		<desc>
			<para>
				Pravega calls the best bands from across the nation for a head on face-off. Audience will witness some truly thrilling performances those promise to send a shiver down their spine. The Pravega Battle of the Bands is an experience that promises to enthral, amaze, and wow spectators and participants alike. Blues, jazz, country music, progressive rock, heavy metal — we welcome it all. The only condition: make the audience groove to your music!
			</para>
			<para><![CDATA[<b>Prizes worth Rs. 30000 at stake!</b>]]></para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[ <CENTER> <b> Co-ordinator: </b> <br>Madhwesh C. R.<br> <a href="mailto:madhwesh@pravega.org" target="_blank">madhwesh@pravega.org</a></CENTER>]]>
			</para>	
		</desc>
		<image>porp.png</image>
		<rules_list>
			<rule>Bands must have a minimum of 3 members and can have a maximum of 7 members.</rule>
			<rule>Participating students must have valid college ID.</rule>
			<rule>Participants must perform in English only.</rule>
			<rule>Bands must register the names of band members and the songs to be performed before they enter the competition.</rule>
			<rule>No individual can be a member of more than one band.</rule>
			<rule>A maximum of 15 mins (prelims)/20 mins (finals) is given to each performance.</rule>
			<rule>Use of profanity and misbehavior on stage will lead to disqualification.</rule>
			<rule>Each part in the final will have equal weightage.</rule>
			<rule>The decision 	by panel of judges will be final and binding.</rule>
			<rule><![CDATA[<b>Rounds:</b>
				<ul style="margin-left:25px;">
					<li>Prelims: Every team will have to present one piece of composition. The top four teams will be selected for the finals.</li>
					<li>Finals: Every team can present any number of compositions in the stipulated time. Repetition of prelim's composition is allowed.</li>
				</ul>]]>
			</rule>
			<rule><![CDATA[<b>Duration:</b>
				<ul style="margin-left:25px;">
					<li>Prelims: 5 mins per team.</li>
					<li>Finals: 10 mins per team.</li>
				</ul>]]>
			</rule>
		</rules_list>
	</event>

	<event>
		<name>Scrapyard Symphonies</name>
		<file_name>scrapyard_symphonies</file_name>
		<subject>Cultural_not</subject>
		<oneline_desc>Pravega invites artists to show the world that they can create music out of scrap, junk and the mundane. The more avant garde the instruments, the better!</oneline_desc>
		<desc>
			<para>
				Find yourself irresistibly tapping a tune on the table while having your morning cereal? Pravega invites artists to show the world that they can create music out of scrap, junk and the mundane. The more avant garde the instruments, the better!
			</para>
			<para>
				Those who play the most popular tunes will win more than just the adulation of the crowd: they will go back with jingling pockets.
			</para>
			<para><![CDATA[<b>Prizes worth Rs. 13000 at stake!</b>]]></para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[ <CENTER> <b> Co-ordinator: </b> <br>Madhwesh C. R.<br> <a href="mailto:madhwesh@pravega.org" target="_blank">madhwesh@pravega.org</a></CENTER>]]>
			</para>
		</desc>
		<image>porp.png</image>
		<rules_list>
			<rule>Participants have to come with their own instruments which will be inspected by the coordinators.</rule>
			<rule>A single team member should register here for the event.</rule>
			<rule>Whatever junk you are going to use, mail us a probable list of the items. Some of those may be provided by us.</rule>
			<rule>No vocals are allowed.</rule>
			<rule>Beatboxing is allowed.</rule>
			<rule>There will be a preliminary round.</rule>
			<rule>Prelims' duration: 5 minutes per team.</rule>
			<rule>The four best teams will be selected for the finals.</rule>
			<rule>Finals Duration: 8 minutes per team, excluding setup. On stage waste of time will lead to penalty.</rule>
			<rule>There is special marking for innovative instruments.</rule>
			<rule>The selection of teams by panel of judges shall be final and binding, and not subject to any further queries, objections or negotiations.</rule>
		</rules_list>
	</event>

	<event>
		<name>30 Seconds to Fame</name>
		<file_name>30_seconds</file_name>
		<subject>Cultural</subject>
		<oneline_desc>Pravega offers you 30 seconds to put on a performance of a lifetime and wow the world with your wildest skills.</oneline_desc>
		<desc>
			<para>
				Pravega offers you 30 seconds to put on a performance of a lifetime and wow the world with your wildest skills.</para>
			<para>
				Half a minute to catapult yourself to fame! This is your chance to get the limelight you’'ve always wanted. This event is essentially a 30 second talent show. You’'ve got the talent, we'’ve got the time. So come and wow us!
			</para>
			<para><![CDATA[<b>Prizes worth Rs. 10000 at stake!</b>]]></para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[ <CENTER> <b> Co-ordinator: </b> <br>Madhwesh C. R.<br> <a href="mailto:madhwesh@pravega.org" target="_blank">madhwesh@pravega.org</a></CENTER>]]>
			</para>	
		</desc>
		<image>porp.png</image>
		<rules_list>
			<rule>The participants will have to describe their act to the coordinators. Only after the act acquires a green signal from the coordinators, will the participant be allowed to perform.</rule>
			<rule>The use of fire, firecrackers, explosives, confetti, and anything which could cause harm to the audience, participant or the arena is strictly prohibited.</rule>
			<rule>Participant is liable for any damage caused to Institute property during the act.</rule>
			<rule>Any performance exceeding 30 seconds will lead to disqualification. There will be a countdown of 5 seconds before the actual 30 seconds begin so as to give the participant breather time.</rule>
		</rules_list>
	</event>

	<event>
		<name><![CDATA[L&#257;sya]]></name>
		<file_name>lasya</file_name>
		<subject>Cultural</subject>
		<oneline_desc>Can your footwork set the stage on fire?</oneline_desc>
		<desc>
			<para>
				An event for those who crave to set the floor on fire! A fine blend of rhythm and poise with a touch of innovation, here’'s an opportunity to bring out the artiste in you. Get ready to sway your hands and tap your feet, for the dance event of Pravega awaits you!
			</para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[
					<b>Judgement Criteria</b><br>
					The participants will be judged on the following:<br><br>
					Theme
					<ul style="margin-left:30px; margin-top:-25px;">
						<li>Theme selection and presentation</li>
						<li>Choreography and synchronization</li>
						<li>Song selection</li>
						<li>Stage presence and style</li>
						<li>Theme depiction</li>
						<li>Costumes (their relevance to theme) and Expressions</li>
						<li>No lyrics, shlokas, aalaaps and fading of words are allowed.</li>
					</ul>
					<br>
					Non-theme
					<ul style="margin-left:30px; margin-top:5px;">
						<li>Creativity and innovation</li>
						<li>Choreography and coordination</li>
						<li>Costumes, Song Selection and Properties</li>
						<li>Stage presence and style</li>
					</ul>
				]]>
			</para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[
					<center>
						<b>Prizes worth Rs.45000 at stake!</b><br>
						1st Prize: Rs.25000<br>
						2nd Prize: Rs.12500<br>
						3rd Prize: Rs.7500
					</center>
				]]>
			</para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[ <CENTER> <b> Co-ordinator: </b> <br>Madhwesh C. R.<br> <a href="mailto:madhwesh@pravega.org" target="_blank">madhwesh@pravega.org</a></CENTER>]]>
			</para>	
		</desc>
		<image>porp.png</image>
		<rules_list>
			<rule>Minimum of 8 and maximum of 15 members per team.</rule>
			<rule>A single team member should register here for the event.</rule>
			<rule>Teams registered must submit their tracks (finals - 10 minutes) one hour before the event in a pen drive and CD in MP3 format and are requested to keep back up.</rule>
			<rule>The following particulars are to be written on the CD: Name of the Team Leader, Phone Number and College Name.</rule>
			<rule>The rules remain the same for the teams getting shortlisted to perform on stage.</rule>
			<rule>Team leaders must pick out spots at the specified time to decide the order of on-stage appearances.</rule>
			<rule>Any number of teams is permitted from a college. But no participant can be a member of more than one team.</rule>
			<rule>In addition to the maximum permissible number of dancers, each team can have a maximum of 3 non-dancers for music, lights, narration.</rule>
			<rule>Remixes of songs can be used.</rule>
			<rule>Variety in songs, costumes and proper utilization of properties yields extra marks.</rule>
			<rule>Violation of rules will lead to disqualification.</rule>
			<rule>Vulgarity in any form is strictly prohibited.</rule>
			<rule>Use of water, fire or any inflammable substance is prohibited.</rule>
			<rule>No additional time will be given for setting up the stage or props. *Props include objects carried by participants, such as sticks, swords, pots etc. Chairs, tables, screens and backdrops come under stage settings.</rule>
			<rule>The decision of the judges is final and no question will be entertained in this regard.</rule>
			<rule>Teams should themselves clear the stage for the next team.</rule>
		</rules_list>
	</event>
	
	<event>
		<name>B-boying Workshop</name>
		<file_name>bboying</file_name>
		<subject>Cultural</subject>
		<oneline_desc>Want to show off in a party or become a pro at break dancing?</oneline_desc>
		<desc>
			<para>
			<![CDATA[
			<table>
				<tr style="margin-bottom:10px;">
					<td style="padding:0px; padding-right:20px; text-align:right; vertical-align:top;"><b>Date:</b></td>
					<td style="padding:0px;">February 1, 2014, 3pm - 5pm</td>
				</tr>
				<tr style="margin-bottom:10px;">
					<td style="padding:0px; padding-right:20px; text-align:right; vertical-align:top;"><b>Duration:</b></td>
					<td style="padding:0px;">2 hours</td>
				</tr>
				<tr style="margin-bottom:10px;">
					<td style="padding:0px; padding-right:20px; text-align:right; vertical-align:top;"><b>Venue:</b></td>
					<td style="padding:0px;">IISc Bangalore</td>
				</tr>
				<tr style="margin-bottom:10px;">
					<td style="padding:0px; padding-right:20px; width:13em; text-align:right; vertical-align:top;"><b>Cost of the workshop:</b></td>
					<td style="padding:0px;">Rs. 150. Registration will be done only onsite on a first come, first serve basis, for 25 seats.</td>
				</tr>
			</table>
			
			<CENTER> <b> Co-ordinator: </b> <br>Harshit Dubey<br> +91 8970054356</CENTER>
			<br>
			<p>
				Featuring BBoy Nas - Naser Al Azzeh, from Black Ice Crew. Naser Al Azzeh is a founder of Black Ice Crew and one of India's best B-boys. A native of Amman, Jordan, Naser is an excellent teacher as well, and will take a personalized workshop of two hours to teach his tips and tricks during Pravega.
			</p>
			
			<p>
				B-boying - also called breakdancing, is a style of street dance that originated among Black and Puerto Rican youths in New York City during the early 1970s.While diverse in the amount of variation available in the dance, b-boying consists of four kinds of movement: toprock, downrock, power moves, and freezes. B-boying is typically danced to hip-hop, funk music, and especially breakbeats, although modern trends allow for much wider varieties of music along certain ranges of tempo and beat patterns.
			</p>
			]]>
			</para>
		</desc>
		<image>logos/mobile_building.jpg</image>
	</event>
	
	<event>
		<name>Crossword Contests</name>
		<file_name>crossword</file_name>
		<subject>Cultural</subject>
		<oneline_desc>3 themed crossword contests: One for each day of Pravega!</oneline_desc>
		<desc>
			<para>Pravega will have a themed crossword contest running on campus everyday!</para>
			<para>You can pick up a copy of the crossword any time during the day at the help desk. Keep ruminating as you walk through our prepossessing campus, and submit the answers when you're done.</para>
			<para>Cash prizes worth Rs. 5000 + goodies at stake!</para>
			<para>PS: The themes will NOT be science related.</para>
		</desc>
		<image>crypto.png</image>
		<rules_list>
			<rule>Pick up the crossword at the help desk any time of the day.</rule>
			<rule>Turn it in before 5 o'clock.</rule>
			<rule>This is a team event - teams of two. (Individual entries also allowed)</rule>
			<rule>Cross-college participation is allowed.</rule>
			<rule>Prizes will be awarded subject to verification of participants identities.</rule>
		</rules_list>
	</event>
	
	<event>
		<name>The Armchair Chemist</name>
		<file_name>armchair_chemist</file_name>
		<subject>Chemistry</subject>
		<oneline_desc>Nothing like some good old problems to brush up your chemistry skills!</oneline_desc>
		<desc>
			<para>Are you that chemist who would rather push arrows and compare free energies to predict products? Do you eschew the messy world of experiment for the convenience of pen and parchment? Armchair Chemist is the event for you! Your fundamental understandings of how jiggling atoms create everything from mercury to marshmallows will be put to the test. </para>
			<para>12th Standard Chemistry is all you need. And no rote expected! (we promise).</para>
			<para><![CDATA[<b>Prizes worth Rs. 10000 at stake!</b>]]></para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[ <CENTER> <b> Co-ordinator: </b> <br>Aravind Rao<br> <a href="mailto:aravind@pravega.org" target="_blank">aravind@pravega.org</a></CENTER>]]>
			</para>	
		</desc>
		<image>porp.png</image>
		<rules_list>
			<rule>Teams of 2 participants.</rule>
			<rule>The competition is a four-hour examination to be attempted by teams of two.</rule>
			<rule>The question paper has two parts, A and B. Part A is objective and Part B involves written explanations.</rule>
			<rule>The teams may use a non-programmable calculator for computations; no other electronic gadgets are allowed.</rule>
		</rules_list>
	</event>
	
	<event>
		<name>Molecular Murals</name>
		<file_name>molecular_murals</file_name>
		<subject>Chemistry</subject>
		<oneline_desc>Synthesise colours and create art!</oneline_desc>
		<desc>
			<para>
				A fun filled event where the chemist dons the artist's cap. First you synthesise colours using chemical reagents and then use them to create art!
			</para>
			<para><![CDATA[<b>Prizes worth Rs. 5000 at stake!</b>]]></para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[ <CENTER> <b> Co-ordinator: </b> <br>Aravind Rao<br> <a href="mailto:aravind@pravega.org" target="_blank">aravind@pravega.org</a></CENTER>]]>
			</para>	
		</desc>
		<image>porp.png</image>
		<rules_list>
			<rule>Participants should register in teams of three.</rule>
			<rule>Participants have to make the colours using their knowledge of chemistry using a given set of chemicals.</rule>
			<rule>They use them to make a work of art, within the stipulated time.</rule>
			<rule>Participants will be evaluated for the aesthetic value of their painting, as well as the application of chemistry to make the paints. </rule>
		</rules_list>
	</event>
	
	<event>
		<name>BASF Carbon Carbon Everywhere</name>
		<file_name>carbon_carbon_everywhere</file_name>
		<subject>Chemistry</subject>
		<oneline_desc>Step into the shoes of an organic chemist for the day!</oneline_desc>
		<desc>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[Think Organic Chemistry is all about boring name-reactions, oddly named molecules and reagents with leviathan names? Well, <i>Carbon Carbon Everywhere</i> is here to bring about a paradigm shift in your thoughts!]]>
			</para>
			
			<para>
				Logic and sound fundamentals are all you require to tackle the challenges in Carbon Carbon everywhere. The prelims will consist of a written quiz featuring thought provoking (when we say thought provoking, we <![CDATA[<i>mean</i>]]> thought provoking) questions with contemporary organic chemistry research as the overarching theme.
			</para>

			<para>
				The teams that make it the finals will dabble a bit with practical organic chemistry, some computational chemistry and take on challenges in interdisciplinary areas like biochemistry and medicine. In short, the finalists get to step into the shoes of an organic chemist for day.
			</para>

			<para>
				And all this with some of the world's best facilities at their disposal! May the best team win!
			</para>
			<para><![CDATA[<b>Prizes worth Rs. 18000 at stake!</b>]]></para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[ <CENTER> <b> Co-ordinator: </b> <br>Aravind Rao<br> <a href="mailto:aravind@pravega.org" target="_blank">aravind@pravega.org</a></CENTER>]]>
			</para>	
		</desc>
		<image>porp.png</image>
		<rules_list>
			<rule>Teams of 3 to 4 members.</rule>
			<rule>Cross-college teams are allowed.</rule>
			<rule>The first round will consist of a written round which will test your fundamentals of chemistry. 12th standard knowledge of chemistry is sufficient.</rule>
			<rule>Five teams will be selected for the finals.</rule>
			<rule>The finals will involve some hands-on tasks involving organic chemistry.</rule>
			<rule>The judges' decision is final and binding.</rule>
		</rules_list>
	</event>
	
	<event>
		<name>Celebrating Chemistry: Online Essay Writing</name>
		<file_name>chemistry_essay</file_name>
		<subject>Chemistry</subject>
		<oneline_desc>Craft an essay on any one of our chemistry related topics.</oneline_desc>
		<desc>
			<para>
				Using your intellect amalgamate your knowledge of language, philosophy, history and chemistry. Use this to put pen to paper and write about the paradigm shifts in chemistry and write about the chemists who brought about these changes.
			</para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[<b>Topics are out! Find them <a href="rulebook/chemistry_online_essay_topics.pdf" target="_blank">here</a>.</b>]]>
			</para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[<b>Last date for submission: January 20th, 2014.</b>]]>
			</para>
			<para><![CDATA[<b>Prizes worth Rs. 10000 at stake!</b>]]></para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[ <CENTER> <b> Co-ordinator: </b> <br>Aravind Rao<br> <a href="mailto:aravind@pravega.org" target="_blank">aravind@pravega.org</a></CENTER>]]>
			</para>	
		</desc>
		<image>porp.png</image>
		<rules_list>
			<rule>The essay must be the original work of the participant. For the sake of aesthetics, citations are not expected. (No references to websites, journals, textbooks etc. This is an aesthetic essay.)  But quotes made by scientists must be quoted along with their names and cannot be used as a normal sentence.  If noticed that the essay is plagiarised, the entry shall be deemed invalid without further notice of the participant.</rule>
			<rule>Each participant can submit only one essay.</rule>
			<rule>There are three topics to choose from. The final prizes will not make the distinction of the topic.</rule>
			<rule>Choose one of the topics and mention the letter code (1/2/3) on your entry. You are free to give the title you think is the best.</rule>
			<rule>The essay should be in English. The essay should run between 1500-2500 words.</rule>
			<rule>Send a pdf file as your entry.</rule>
			<rule>All the participants are exclusively invited to the fest. The winners shall be announced during the fest in the campus.</rule>
			<rule><![CDATA[Essays must be submitted by 20th January, 2014 to <a href="mailto:aravind@pravega.org" target="_blank">aravind@pravega.org</a>.]]></rule>
		</rules_list>
	</event>
	
	<event>
		<name>The Armchair Physicist</name>
		<file_name>armchair_physicist</file_name>
		<subject>Physics</subject>
		<oneline_desc>Subject your understanding of the fundamentals of physics to a test of fire. Only the true physicist will emerge unscathed.</oneline_desc>
		<desc>
			<para>
				Are you amongst those who disregard the messy world of experiment for the abstract beauty of theory and equations? Would you rather unravel the mysteries of the universe with pen and parchment? This is the event for you! Get ready to subject your conceptual understanding of physics to a test of fire.  Only the true physicist will emerge unscathed.
			</para>
			<para><![CDATA[<b>Prizes worth Rs. 10000 at stake!</b>]]></para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[ <CENTER> <b> Co-ordinator: </b> <br>Shreyas Gupta<br> <a href="mailto:shreyas@pravega.org" target="_blank">shreyas@pravega.org</a></CENTER>]]>
			</para>	
		</desc>
		<image></image>
		<rules_list>
			<rule>A team can have three people at maximum.</rule>
			<rule> No more knowledge than 12th grade Physics  is required.</rule>
			<rule>The event will comprise two rounds: The preliminary will be a written examination of five questions and the four highest scoring teams will move on to the finals.</rule>
			<rule> The teams will be ranked on the basis of their performance in the preliminary round.</rule>
			<rule> In the final round, four problems will be presented to the teams.</rule>
			<rule> Each team chooses a problem to solve in the order of their ranking.</rule>
			<rule> The teams will then be allowed to work on their respective problems in seclusion for thirty minutes after which they will present their solutions to the audience and the other teams, in the reverse order of their ranking.</rule>
			<rule> The presentations will be fifteen minutes each after which first the other teams and then the audience are allowed to challenge the solution.</rule>
			<rule> The defence and challenge will both count towards the points that a team is awarded.</rule>
			<rule> There will be prizes for the audience for pointing out fallacies in the solution.</rule>
			<rule> An eminent physicist will serve as the judge.</rule>				
		</rules_list>
	</event>
	
	<event>
		<name>Experimental Physics</name>
		<file_name>experimental_physics</file_name>
		<subject>Physics</subject>
		<oneline_desc>Step into the shoes of an experimental physicist and compete to complete a series of engaging and brain-taxing tasks.</oneline_desc>
		<desc>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[€œThe laboratory is the supreme court of physics where God renders judgement.
				<div style="margin-top:-35px;">&ndash;Lewis C. Epstein</div>]]>
			</para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[
					<center>
						<img style="position: relative; display: inline-block; width:auto; width: 250px;" src="images/logos/didactic_systems.png" /><br>
						Event sponsored by Didactic Systems.
					</center>
				]]>
			</para>
			<para>
				Pravega in association with Didactic Systems provides participants with a unique opportunity to step into the shoes of an experimental physicist for a day. Participants will have to battle Murphy€'s law, mischance and rotten luck and perform a series of engaging yet brain-taxing experiments.
			</para>
			<para>
				An event for both hard-core Physics enthusiasts as well as ingenious engineers! 
			</para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[
				<center><b>Online Round Questions released! <a href="rulebook/experimental_physics_questions.docx" target="_blank">Download them here!</a><br>Submissions are to be made to <a href="mailto:shreyas@pravega.org" target="_blank">shreyas@pravega.org</a></b></center>
				]]>
			</para>
			<para><![CDATA[<b>Prizes worth Rs. 15000 at stake!</b>]]></para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[ <CENTER> <b> Co-ordinator: </b> <br>Shreyas Gupta<br> <a href="mailto:shreyas@pravega.org" target="_blank">shreyas@pravega.org</a></CENTER>]]>
			</para>	
		</desc>
		<image></image>
		<rules_list>
			<rule>The competition will consist of 2 rounds:</rule>
			<rule>Prelims
				<![CDATA[
				<ol style="margin-left:20px; list-style-type:lower-alpha;">
					<li>Online test before Pravega. Team registrations will be online.</li>
					<li>Written test during Pravega. Team registrations will be online as well as on the spot. Teams unsuccessful in the online test can also participate in this round.</li>
					<li>The test will comprise of MCQ-type questions and subjective-type questions.</li>
					<li>2 teams will qualify for the Final Round from the online test and 3 teams will qualify for the Final Round from the written test during Pravega.</li>
					<li>Participants will be tested for fundamental concepts of physics, fundamentals of experimentation skills, analysis of data and other similar topics related to experimental physics.</li>
				</ol>
				]]>
			</rule>
			<rule>Final Round
				<![CDATA[
					<ol style="margin-left:20px; list-style-type:lower-alpha;">
					  <li>Only 5 teams will enter the final round. All the teams will get a time of 5 hours.</li>
					  <li>The teams will be provided with an unassembled kit and a set of tasks. On finishing the first task the teams can proceed to the next task and gain bonus points if they finish the other tasks.</li>
					  <li>The teams will be provided with a programmable device to record the data. They will be able to record manually also but programming the device and using it to record the data may give the team an advantage in recording the data.</li>
					  <li>The participants do not have to bring anything to the event. All the resources required for the competition will be provided to the participants on the spot.</li>
					</ol>
				]]>
			</rule>
			<rule>Note: The teams should consist of maximum of 4 members. The team members should be undergraduates.</rule>
		</rules_list>
	</event>
	
	<event>
		<name>Master the Tides</name>
		<file_name>master_the_tides</file_name>
		<subject>PhysicsGONE</subject>
		<oneline_desc>Navigate a raft through the twist and turns of a turbulent water course.</oneline_desc>
		<desc>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[Pravega has created its own torrential tributary&mdash;a scaled-down version of a river-rafting course that will be the hardest test a man-made vessel ever saw. This event will attract engineers who can both think as well as work with their hands and can implement the difficult concepts of fluid dynamics in reality. Participants are required to construct a raft-like platform that is capable of navigating the water-track. May the best shipwright win!]]>
			</para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[ <CENTER> <b> Co-ordinator: </b> <br>Shreyas Gupta<br> <a href="mailto:shreyas@pravega.org" target="_blank">shreyas@pravega.org</a></CENTER>]]>
			</para>	
		</desc>
		<image></image>
		<rules_list>
			<rule>The objective is to create a course-worthy raft using small homeopathy bottles, paper, thread, feviquick, glue and sticks.</rule>
			<rule>Registration may be online or onsite, with a first-come-first-serve basis that favours online registrations. For online registration, the team is required to solve 10 multiple-choice questions online.</rule>
			<rule>A team may consist of a maximum of two members.</rule>
			<rule>Participants may bring homemade platforms or make them on the spot; materials will be provided.</rule>
			<rule><![CDATA[A 6 ft &times; 4 ft sized water track having scaled up design of the miniature model will be elevated above a tub of water.]]></rule>
			<rule><![CDATA[A cube of dimensions 1"&times;1"&times;1" and average density 2.4 g/cc will have to be transported as cargo on the raft along the course of the track. The top half of the cube should be uncovered. This cube is placed by the organizer as indicated by the participating team.]]></rule>
			<rule>One hour is given for making or modifying the platform. The platforms may not be modified after commencement of the trials. If a team so wishes, they may opt for at most one second attempt.The platform may be modified during the thirty minutes between the two sets of trials.</rule>
			<rule><![CDATA[The score per run is calculated by the following formula: <div style="text-align:center;">T<sub>0</sub> &minus; T + k &times; Checkpoints + Bonus &minus; Penalty</div> where T<sub>0</sub> and k are some appropriate constants, T is the time taken for this run, and the bonus and penalty are based on the discretion of the judges.]]></rule>
			<rule><![CDATA[If the team has chosen for a second attempt, their score is calculated by the following formula:
				<div style="text-align: center;">1/100 &times; ((Attempt 1 Score) &times; <i>x</i> &minus; (Attempt 2 Score) &times; (1&minus;<i>x</i>))</div>
				The value of x is chosen by the team, must lie between 25 and 75, and must be chosen between the two trials. The scores per attempt are determined by the formula in point 8.]]>
			</rule>
		</rules_list>
	</event>

 	<event>
 		<name>Tri-D Chess</name>
		<file_name>tri_d_chess</file_name>
	 	<subject>Physics</subject>
 		<oneline_desc>A novel spin-off of good old chess, you have to worry about 3 dimensions instead of 2 in Tri-D chess!</oneline_desc>
		<desc>
			<para>
				For those who love chess, prepare to raise your game to the third dimension. Fans of The Big Bang Theory and Star Trek will recognize this game of Tri-D Chess.
			</para>
			<para>
				A spin-off of the usual chess, in Tri-D Chess the pawns will be able to move between three boards arranged in three planes. The ensuing logical complexity in making moves will push the participants'€™ brains to the limit.
			</para>
			<para><![CDATA[<b>Prizes worth Rs. 8000 at stake!</b>]]></para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[ <CENTER> <b> Co-ordinator: </b> <br>Shreyas Gupta<br> <a href="mailto:shreyas@pravega.org" target="_blank">shreyas@pravega.org</a></CENTER>]]>
			</para>	
		</desc>
		<image></image>
		<rules_list>
			<rule>It is an individual event with on-spot registration.</rule>
			<rule>Timing: Participants start with a time of 25 minutes.</rule>
			<rule>In the event of a participant using up all his time, he will be considered to have lost the match.</rule>
			<rule>Other standard 3-D chess rules apply. They can be viewed <![CDATA[<a href="http://home.arcor.de/jens.meder/3dschach/chess3d.htm" target="_blank">here</a>]]>.</rule>
			<rule>Practice games can be played at <![CDATA[<a href="http://www.parmen.com" target="_blank">parmen.com</a>]]>.</rule>
			<rule>Participants will face off against each other in a knockout format. Pairing will be done randomly.</rule>
		</rules_list>
	</event>
	
	<event>
		<name>Colours from the Grey</name>
		<file_name>colours_from_the_grey</file_name>
		<subject>Biology</subject>
		<oneline_desc>It's all about integrating your creativity and logical insights to crack challenging biological puzzles.</oneline_desc>
		<desc>
			<para>
				An event that promises to send your minds down a path of intellectual bliss, throwing open a challenge to all those young biologists, who are willing to integrate their logical and creative sides to crack the most unanticipated, wacky, and mind boggling puzzles, taking their understanding of the biological world to new heights.
			</para>
			<para><![CDATA[<b>Prizes worth Rs. 20000 at stake!</b>]]></para>
			<para><![CDATA[<b><a href="rulebook/colours_from_the_grey.pdf">Rules for the final round of Colours From The Grey</a></b>]]></para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[ <CENTER> <b> Co-ordinator: </b> <br>Siddharth Kankaria<br> <a href="mailto:siddharth@pravega.org" target="_blank">siddharth@pravega.org</a></CENTER>]]>
			</para>	
		</desc>
		<image></image>
		<rules_list>
			<rule>Teams can have at most 3 members.</rule>
			<rule>The event consists of two rounds.</rule>
			<rule>The preliminary round will require the participants to solve a set of puzzles/questions within a stipulated time of 1 hour.</rule>
			<rule>The top-scoring teams will be chosen for the finals based on the scores of the preliminary round.</rule>
			<rule>The final round, which will be held on the same day, will last for about 2 hours.</rule>
			<rule>The decision of the judges is final and binding.</rule>
			<rule>The format, rules and regulations of the final round will be revealed very soon. Stay tuned to this page for an adrenaline rush! </rule>
		</rules_list>
	</event>
	
	<event>
		<name>Lexico Bio</name>
		<file_name>lexico_bio</file_name>
		<subject>Biology</subject>
		<oneline_desc>Calling all biology enthusiasts to test their lexicographical skills!</oneline_desc>
		<desc>
			<para>
		        <![CDATA[Do you fancy yourself as the queen (or king, if you wish so) bee of spelling? Lexico Bio offers just the right opportunity for everyone to drench themselves in a spell-o-mania! It is our home-grown version of the internationally recognised Spell Bees, but with a slight twist&mdash;all the words that you would be given to spell will be inspired from the biological sciences.]]>
			</para>
			<para>	
				Lexico Bio is a very thoughtfully designed game to provide a fun opportunity for even the non-biologists to acquaint themselves with the amazingly diverse world of biological terms. 
			</para>
			<para><![CDATA[<b>Prizes worth Rs. 6000 at stake!</b>]]></para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[ <CENTER> <b> Co-ordinator: </b> <br>Siddharth Kankaria<br> <a href="mailto:siddharth@pravega.org" target="_blank">siddharth@pravega.org</a></CENTER>]]>
			</para>	
		</desc>
		<image></image>
		<rules_list>
			<rule>The event consists of three rounds.</rule>
			<rule>Round 1 will be conducted in event registration stalls where the participants will have to write down the spellings of ten biological terms recited to them on spot. The top 30 scorers would move on to the next round, which will be held the next day.</rule>
			<rule>Similarly, in round two, the qualified participants will gather and spell twenty given words in writing. The top 6 scorers will move to round three which will be held on the same day.</rule>
			<rule>Round three will be an oral round where the 6 selected participants will be called on to the stage individually to spell.</rule>
			<rule>Additional rules and regulations concerning the competition will be described clearly prior to the commencement of each round.</rule>
		</rules_list> 
	</event>
	
	<event>
		<name><![CDATA[The Fourth R &ndash; Re-Envision]]></name>
		<file_name>fourth-r</file_name>
		<subject>Biology</subject>
		<oneline_desc>Showcase your proficiency in cinematography and let your imagination go "naturally green"!</oneline_desc>
		<desc>
			<para>
		        "Vision is the art of seeing what is invisible to others."
				<![CDATA[
				<div style="width: 100%; text-align: right; margin-top: -20px;">&ndash; Jonathan Swift</div>
				]]>
			</para>
			<para>
				The Fourth R is about re-envisioning everything and anything about nature around you. It is about seeing, observing, interpreting and sharing something which is unseen about the environment around us, and what generally goes unnoticed by us in the flow of daily life; be it the flight of a butterfly, the working of a small ecosystem in your backyard, or the rain eroding away the topsoil in your neighbourhood! Grab a camera and make a small video about anything that fascinates you about nature, and share a source of beauty, a message, or your concern with us.
			</para>
			<para><![CDATA[<b>Prizes worth Rs. 4000 at stake!</b>]]></para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[ <CENTER> <b> Co-ordinator: </b> <br>Siddharth Kankaria<br> <a href="mailto:siddharth@pravega.org" target="_blank">siddharth@pravega.org</a></CENTER>]]>
			</para>	
		</desc>
		<image></image>
		<rules_list>
			<rule><![CDATA[Videos must be of minimum resolution: 640&times;480, and should not exceed beyond 12 minutes in duration.]]></rule>
			<rule>There can be a maximum of five members per team.</rule>
			<rule>Your video must be uploaded newly onto YouTube through your own channel. The description to your video must mention it as an entry to the contest and should carry back a link to the Pravega homepage.</rule>
			<rule><![CDATA[You have to send the link of your YouTube video to: <a href="mailto:biology@pravega.org">biology@pravega.org</a>, latest by 27th January, 2014.]]></rule>
			<rule>The decision of the judges is final and binding.</rule>
			<rule>Plagiarism won't be tolerated at any level and will result in immediate disqualification. It is not encouraged to use videos shot by other people and any such use will lead to a penalty. However, if you feel it is essential to your entry's context, please cite the source of the external video used.</rule>
		</rules_list> 
	</event>
	
	<event>
		<name>The Act of Life</name>
		<file_name>act_of_life</file_name>
		<subject>Biology</subject>
		<oneline_desc>A unique mix of dumb charades and theatre involving biological concepts.</oneline_desc>
		<desc>
			<para>
		         Heard of dumb charades in biology? With the usage of elements of drama and mime, you would be expected to enact out biological terms and phenomena, while your team guesses the word. You cannot split any word where the split-up word itself isn't a biological term itself. All the rounds will have variations of this general theme of biology and theatre intertwined together.
			</para>
			<para>
				So buckle up and get ready to unleash the actor in you!
			</para>
			<para><![CDATA[<b>Prizes worth Rs. 4000 at stake!</b>]]></para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[ <CENTER> <b> Co-ordinator: </b> <br>Siddharth Kankaria<br> <a href="mailto:siddharth@pravega.org" target="_blank">siddharth@pravega.org</a></CENTER>]]>
			</para>	
		</desc>
		<image></image>
		<rules_list>
			<rule>Each team should consist of exactly 4 members.</rule>
			<rule>The participants are not allowed to use any form of written or spoken language to express the topic. They can only use mime, acting and hand movements to describe the biological phenomena.</rule>
			<rule>Sign language communication between actor and guesser is allowed. However, usage of syllables, phonetics or alphabets through any signalling method would lead to instant disqualification.</rule>
			<rule>The participants cannot split the words into any part, until and unless the split words itself is a completely meaningful biological term. If the splitting of a word results in two smaller words, only one of which is a biological term, then the actor can only enact out the sub-word with biological meaning.</rule>
			<rule>The teams have to send us a set of 20 enactable biological terms (phenomena) by 29th January, 2014 to <![CDATA[<a href="mailto:biology@pravega.org">biology@pravega.org</a>]]>. 10 topics will be reselected from this list and be given back to the team for usage in one of the rounds.</rule>
			<rule>There will be three rounds in total. </rule>
			<rule>In the first round, any one person from each team will have to act out words written on flash cards, one after the other for 2 minutes, while the audience has to guess. The team which skips the least number of words in the set of ordered flash cards, and makes the audience correctly guess the maximum number of words over a duration of 2 minutes, scores the most points.</rule>
			<rule>In the second round, all four members of a team will be given a biological phenomenon to act out together, while the other teams would try to guess the phenomena. The team which guesses the phenomena correctly would score some points, and the team enacting out would also score some points. </rule>
			<rule>In the third round, any one member of a team will be given a biological term, which he has enact out to the second member of his team, with both members remaining completely mute, while the third and fourth members are physically isolated from the stage. Then, the second member enacts out the topic to the third member with both members allowed to communicate via sign language, while the fourth member is still far away. Finally, the third member enacts the word out to the fourth member, with the last member being allowed to vocally speak out the words while guessing them. The aim of this round is to ensure that the word given to first person reaches the last person intact! The teams would be judged on their speed, accuracy, creative use of acting/mime skills, as well as coordination. </rule>
			<rule>The points of each round will be summed in total. The team with the most points at the end of the 3 rounds would win the event.</rule>
		</rules_list> 
	</event>
	
	<event>
		<name>TurnCoat</name>
		<file_name>turncoat</file_name>
		<subject>Biology</subject>
		<oneline_desc>Good ol' debates in a new avatar - switch sides, argue and counter-argue on fresh topics from biology and environmental sciences.</oneline_desc>
		<desc>
			<para>
		        This competition is for all the indomitable debate fiends who can argue for both sides of the coin, and win despite changing sides midway through their arguments<![CDATA[&mdash;]]>and this is exactly what you have to do here! The debate involves you to "turn your coat" i.e. switch over and argue for the other side, instantaneously at the press of a buzzer during the debate. The moment of switching over from 'for' to 'against' views is decided by the judges and the number of such reversals is also unknown to the participant and is at the discretion of the judges.
			</para>
			<para>So prepare yourselves! Can you be an equally convincing Brutus and Mark Anthony, and sway the Romans in tune with the buzzer?!</para>
			<para><![CDATA[<b>Prizes worth Rs. 10000 at stake!</b>]]></para>
			<para><![CDATA[<b>Finals topics are out! <a href="rulebook/turncoat_topics_finals.pdf">Find them here</a>.</b>]]></para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[ <CENTER> <b> Co-ordinator: </b> <br>Siddharth Kankaria<br> <a href="mailto:siddharth@pravega.org" target="_blank">siddharth@pravega.org</a></CENTER>]]>
			</para>	
		</desc>
		<image></image>
		<rules_list>
			<rule>It is an individual event.</rule>
			<rule>Only a maximum of 40 teams can be accommodated in this event, based on a first-come, first-serve basis. The last date for registrations is 30th January, 2014</rule>
			<rule>10 topics for the Prelims will be uploaded two weeks in advance. Each participant can choose any one of the given topics, and email us their first two preferences to <![CDATA[<a href="mailto:biology@pravega.org">biology@pravega.org</a>]]> with the subject line "Chosen Topic for TurnCoat Prelims". Each topic can be chosen by a maximum of 5 people, which will be allotted to participants on a first-come, first-serve basis. We will confirm the allotment of your topic of choice, within a day. </rule>
			<rule>All the topics for this event will be related to biology/environmental science, and will be relevant to the scientific community and the society, in general, from the perspective of their research, application, and impacts.</rule>
			<rule>Prelims: The time limit for each speaker would be tentatively 2 minutes. The speaker can start by speaking either 'For the motion' or 'Against the motion'. However, at any time during the interval of his/her argument, any of the jury members can ring the buzzer, and the speaker would have to immediately switch his side, i.e. from 'For' to 'Against' the motion or vice-versa. A maximum of only 3 such switches would be asked of each speaker.</rule>
			<rule>Finals: There will be 6 finalists chosen after the prelims. The topics for the finals would be released on 29th January evening, and all the participants are expected to have a general idea about the issues concerning each of the 6 topics. On the day of the finals (1st February), each participant would be allotted any one of the 6 topics, and an additional preparation time of 30 min will be given before the Final round commences. Use of internet during these 30 minutes is not allowed, however, speakers may get along any relevant books, notes or pre-downloaded material along with them for their preparations, if they wish so. Each speaker would be expected to speak for 4 minutes, which will be followed by a 2 minute rebuttal, in which both the judges as well as the other participants can participate. The number of turncoat moments and a few other twists in this round, will be revealed just before the final round commences. </rule>
			<rule>The participants are allowed to keep a small sheet of paper in their hands for referring to points, both during the Prelims and the Final rounds</rule>
			<rule>Marking would be based on content (quantity, quality, jargon-free delivery, accessibility to all), clarity of expression, confidence, transition/flow of arguments (especially during switching), interjection skills and other relevant parameters.</rule>
			<rule>The decisions of the judges will be final and binding.</rule>
		</rules_list>
	</event>
	
	<event>
		<name>Apocalypse Now!</name>
		<file_name>apocalypse_now</file_name>
		<subject>Math</subject>
		<oneline_desc>It's up to you to save the world from impending doom. And math is your sole weapon!</oneline_desc>
		<desc>
			<para>
				The world is hovering on the brink of collapse, held back only by the greed of man. In an almost 'apocalyptic' scenario, epidemics are raging through the peoples of a sadder and more desolate future.
			</para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[The ability to research and manufacture drugs to combat them lies with a few monolithic corporations, which have developed so far on a primal impulse special only to man&mdash;profit!]]>
			</para>
			<para>
				Participants will form teams and take on the mantle of disease-ridden countries and money-minded companies and try to out-think their competition in order to survive and thrive.
			</para>
			<para><![CDATA[<b>Prizes worth Rs. 12000 at stake!</b>]]></para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[ <CENTER> <b> Co-ordinator: </b> <br>Sudhanva Kamath<br> <a href="mailto:sudhanva@pravega.org" target="_blank">sudhanva@pravega.org</a></CENTER>]]>
			</para>	
		</desc>
		<image>apo.png</image>
		<rules_list>
			<rule>Participants will need to form teams of two in order to take part in this event.</rule>
			<rule>This competition will occur in two stages - the prelims and the finals.</rule>
			<rule>The prelims require the team to solve a set of game theory and mathematical optimization problems over a period of one and a half hours - the twelve teams to do best will proceed to the finals.</rule>
			<rule>The finals will take place as a three-hour event.</rule>
			<rule>Teams will be assigned the role of companies or countries; there will be six companies and six countries.</rule>
			<rule>Company teams are required to maximise their profit in order to win the games.</rule>
			<rule>Country teams are required to maximise the distance from midnight in their Apocalypse clocks - the closer this parameter of destruction reads to midnight, the nearer is the nation to the breakdown of civilisation.</rule>
			<rule>The teams may interact with each other openly in the competition arena - formation of deals will occur through their computer terminals (these are provided by us).</rule>
			<rule> The terminals will also give them vital statistics about themselves and relevant variables of other teams.</rule>
			<rule>Companies may acquire resources from countries for money - they will need to do so in order to research cures to diseases.</rule>
			<rule>The research of a company on a specific drug is successful after a length of time determined by a function of the rate of expenditure of money in that project; when this happens, that company possesses the blueprint for that drug with characteristics of efficacy and cost that depend on the manner in which that team invested in the research for that drug.</rule>
			<rule>The blueprint may be traded.</rule>
			<rule>If a company possesses the blueprint for a drug, they may put it into production at a certain cost.</rule>
			<rule> After an interval of time determined by the nature of the drug, the company will possess marketable quantities of the doses of that drug.</rule>
			<rule>Countries may buy drugs from companies and administer them to their populations - this reduces the rate at which the population is dying.</rule>
			<rule>The algorithms by which the game will run will be revealed only at the beginning of the game - teams will also have to contend with surprise feature with which they may get ahead.</rule>
			<rule>At the end of the game, the country and the company to do best in terms of distance from midnight and profit gained will be said to have won.</rule>		</rules_list>
	</event>

	<event>
		<name>Crypto</name>
		<file_name>crypto</file_name>
		<subject>Math</subject>
		<oneline_desc>"Three can keep a secret only if two are dead."</oneline_desc>
		<desc>
			<para>Ahoy, puzzle lovers! Welcome aboard.</para>
			<para><![CDATA[In Crypto, you will have to identify and crack ciphers&mdash;and make some of your own too. This event revolves around having an acute eye for detail: seeing patterns in seeming randomness, perceiving order in apparent chaos and the proprieties in the pandemonium.]]></para>
			<para>Do you have an uncanny ability to reconstruct the big picture from the jigsaw? Crypto is the event for you!</para>
			<para>Like actual cryptography, this event will push your ingenuity, quick thinking, and mathematical intuition to the limit.</para>
			<para>Happy decrypting!</para>
			<para><![CDATA[<b>Prizes worth Rs. 12000 at stake!</b>]]></para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[ <CENTER> <b> Co-ordinator: </b> <br>Sudhanva Kamath<br> <a href="mailto:sudhanva@pravega.org" target="_blank">sudhanva@pravega.org</a></CENTER>]]>
			</para>
		</desc>
		<image>apo.png</image>
		<rules_list>
			<rule>There can be a maximum of 3 members per team. Team members need not be from the same institution.</rule>
			<rule>This event will be held in two stages - the prelims and the finals.</rule>
			<rule>The questions are designed to discern the teams' puzzle and cipher-solving ability.</rule> 
			<rule>The judges' decision will be final and binding. Six teams will enter the finals.</rule>
		</rules_list>
	</event>
	
	<event>
		<name>Samasya</name>
		<file_name>samasya</file_name>
		<subject>Math</subject>
		<oneline_desc>The test of the most ancient intellectual art: the art of problem solving</oneline_desc>
		<desc>
			<para>
				<![CDATA["Mathematics, rightly viewed, possesses not only truth, but supreme beauty&mdash;a beauty cold and austere, like that of sculpture, without appeal to any part of our weaker nature, without the gorgeous trappings of painting or music, yet sublimely pure, and capable of a stern perfection such as only the greatest art can show."
				<div style="text-align:right; margin-top:-35px;">&ndash; Bertrand Russel</div>]]>
			</para>
			<para>
				Are you the kind of nut who views math as art? Who draws his life essence from the sublime poetry of numbers? The kind whose raison d'être is the aha! moment that fortuitously gives away a mathematical insight? Well, good news. We like those kinds of nuts.
			</para>
			<para>
				This is the platform for you to pit your mettle against India's best mathletes. The questions will be hard (and interesting), but not quite as hard as the competition. Things to bring along: a bucketful of intuition, as many leaps-of-imagination as you can lug, and some Felix Felicis to goad you headfirst into an aha! moment.
			</para>
			<para><![CDATA[<b>Prizes worth Rs. 10000 at stake!</b>]]></para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[ <CENTER> <b> Co-ordinator: </b> <br>Sudhanva Kamath<br> <a href="mailto:sudhanva@pravega.org" target="_blank">sudhanva@pravega.org</a></CENTER>]]>
			</para>	

		</desc>
		<image>Samasya.png</image>
		<rules_list>
			<rule>This event is four hours long.</rule>
			<rule>The paper is in the standard Olympiad format.</rule>
			<rule>High school math is a necessary and sufficient pre-requisite.</rule>
			<rule>The judges' decisions are peer-reviewed and are final.</rule>
		</rules_list>
	</event>
	
	
	<event>
		<name>Publish or Perish</name>
		<file_name>publish_or_perish</file_name>
		<subject>Math</subject>
		<oneline_desc>Experience the 'kill' joy of having to come up with a paper with real scientists.</oneline_desc>
		<desc>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[Getting a PhD can be a truly herculean task&mdash;especially if your Professor is the sort we have in Publish or Perish! In this event, the participating teams have to try and get the 'Professor' to co-author a paper with them&mdash;standing in their way are other students, and each other.]]>
			</para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[The Professor will randomly choose to work in a specific field&mdash;if a team wishes to increase the Professor's interest in their own field, they will have to answer questions of varying difficulty.]]>
			</para>
			<para>
				This fundamental randomness, as well as a few other quirks of our Professor, make for an event that is both fun and challenging. 
			</para>
			<para><![CDATA[<b>Prizes worth Rs. 12000 at stake!</b>]]></para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[ <CENTER> <b> Co-ordinator: </b> <br>Sudhanva Kamath<br> <a href="mailto:sudhanva@pravega.org" target="_blank">sudhanva@pravega.org</a></CENTER>]]>
			</para>	
		</desc>
		<image>porp.png</image>
		<rules_list>
			<rule>Teams can have at most 3 members.</rule>
			<rule>This event consists of two rounds - the prelims and the finals.</rule>
			<rule>In the prelims, teams will have to solve the given set of problems in 90 minutes.</rule>
			<rule>The six best teams will be chosen for the finals.</rule>
		</rules_list>
	</event>
	
	<event>
		<name>Online Math Challenge</name>
		<file_name>online_math_challenge</file_name>
		<subject>Math</subject>
		<oneline_desc>Pravega presents the Online Math Challenge in association with Gonitsora.com.</oneline_desc>
		<desc>
			<para>We have four interestingly crafted puzzles for you to solve. They look deceptively simple, but the answers will force you to think beyond the conventional! Also, no advanced mathematics is required. Just 12th standard math, applied right, should fetch you the answers.</para>
			<para><![CDATA[<a href="online_math_challenge_problems.pdf" target="_blank">Download the problem set.</a>]]></para>
			<para>Mail your answers to gonitsora@pravega.org before 20th January.(You can mail answers one-at-a-time if you wish)</para>
			<para><![CDATA[<b>Prizes</b>: <br>Winner: Rs. 2000<br>Runners: Rs. 1000]]></para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[ <CENTER> <b>Winners announced!</b></center>
				<ul style="margin-left: 25px;">
					<li>1st prize: Karthik V</li>
					<li>2nd prize: 3 way tie between:	
						<ul style="margin-left: 45px;">
							<li>Jabir Ali K
							<li>Anurag Poddar
							<li>Samrat Navneet</li>
						</ul>
					</li>
				</ul>
				]]>
			</para>	
		</desc>
		<image>apo.png</image>
		<rules_list>
			<rule>Each of the questions carry equal weightage.</rule>
			<rule>The solutions should be neatly written and then scanned or typed and should be emailed to <![CDATA[<a href="mailto:gonitsora@pravega.org">gonitsora@pravega.org</a>]]> before January 20th, 2014.</rule>
			<rule>Extra observations or comments will be awarded with extra points, but be brief and logical.</rule>
			<rule>There can be more than one solution to a problem, and extra points would be awarded if someone gives more than one solution. </rule>
			<rule>No team entries allowed.</rule>
			<rule>All students from any educational institutions are permitted to participate.</rule>
			<rule>Prizes will be awarded after verification of the participant's identity.</rule>
			<rule>Winner will be declared based on number of correct answers and time taken to solve.</rule>
		</rules_list>
	</event>
	
	<event>
		<name>Online Programming Contest</name>
		<file_name>opc</file_name>
		<subject>Engineering</subject>
		<oneline_desc>Pit your brain cells against India's best programmers. There's 18K at stake here!</oneline_desc>
		<desc>
			<para><![CDATA[<b>The contest is now over.</b>]]></para>
			<para>
				Does your pinky twitch for the semicolon at the end of every sentence? Has 1024 displaced 1000 as a 'round figure' in your head? Do you sincerely believe that "To iterate is human, to recurse divine"? Then Pravega online programming contest is the place for you to be on November 9th!
			</para>
			<para>
				Get ready for agonisingly interesting challenges which guarantee to fire your synapses into overdrive. 
			</para>
			<para>
				Pro tip: Ingenuity, quick thinking and resourcefulness will help, as will nimble fingers. 
			</para>
		</desc>
		<image>porp.png</image>
		<rules_list>
			<rule>The contest will be for 2 hours and will have 3 questions. </rule>
			<rule>The contest will be on Saturday, 9th November, 2013 from 21:00 IST to 23:00 IST.</rule>
			<rule><![CDATA[The contest page on CodeChef is available at <a href="http://www.codechef.com/PRVG2014/">www.codechef.com/PRVG2014/</a>.]]></rule>
			<rule>This is a team contest. A team can consist of at most 3 members. One person cannot be a part of more than one team.</rule>
			<rule>The contest is open to everyone but only undergraduates or high school students from India are eligible to win the prizes. Professionals, graduate students, etc. are not eligible to win prizes.</rule>
			<rule>Cross-college teams are allowed.</rule>
			<rule>To be eligible to win prizes, all team members have to be registered on both pravega.org and codechef.com.</rule>
			<rule>Any participant found to be indulging in any form of malpractice will be immediately disqualified.</rule>
			<rule>
				<![CDATA[
				The total amount of prizes to be won is INR 18,000.
					<ul style="margin-left:20px;">
						<li> First Prize of INR 10,000.</li>
						<li> Second Prize of INR 5,000.</li>
						<li> Third Prize of INR 3,000.</li>
					</ul>]]>
			</rule>
			<rule>The constraints on time, memory, etc. shall be specified separately for each problem.</rule>
			<rule>Solutions have to be submitted in C, C++ or Java only.</rule>
			<rule>All participants are expected to abide by the CodeChef Code of Conduct.</rule>
			<rule>Each program will be tested based on our critical test data. However output and input should be exactly as specified in the samples provided. </rule>
			<rule>Each question has a specified number of points allotted to it. Users are ranked according to the most points obtained. Ties will be broken by the total time for each user, in ascending order of time.</rule>
			<rule>Any participant found to be indulging in any form of malpractice will be immediately disqualified.</rule>
			<rule>The decision of the organizers in declaring the results will be final. No queries in this regard will be entertained.</rule>
		</rules_list>
	</event>
	
	<event>
		<name>Remote Controlled Car Race</name>
		<file_name>remote_controlled_car_race</file_name>
		<subject>Engineering</subject>
		<oneline_desc>Ever experienced the adrenaline-rush while racing? Experience it again as your remote controlled car races through an obstacle filled track.</oneline_desc>
		<desc>
			<para>
				This event is the perfect platform to apply the engineering fundas you have learned over the years. Build a remote controlled car capable of tackling off-road situations. Use any conceivable scientific principle at your disposal, but don't forget to make your car tough and fast.
			</para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[<b>The problem statement is out! <a href="remote_controlled_car_race_problem_statement.pdf" target="_blank">Find it here.</a></b>]]>
			</para>
			<para><![CDATA[<b>Prizes worth Rs. 18000 at stake!</b>]]></para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[ <CENTER> <b> Co-ordinator: </b> <br>Amitabh Shrivastava<br> <a href="mailto:amitabh@pravega.org" target="_blank">amitabh@pravega.org</a></CENTER>]]>
			</para>	
		</desc>
		<image>porp.png</image>
		<rules_list>
			<rule>Teams can have a maximum of 4 members.</rule>
			<rule>Participants have to bring their own car.</rule>
			<rule>The cars will hit the track one at a time.</rule>
			<rule>The track will be 30 cm wide.</rule>
			<rule>The car must be self-built.</rule>
			 <rule><![CDATA[Only electric cars with <15V battery are allowed.]]></rule>
			 <rule>The objective is to cover the track as quickly as possible.</rule>
			 <rule>Refer to the problem statement for further details.</rule>
		</rules_list>
	</event>
	
	<event>
		<name>Antipyretic Antics</name>
		<file_name>antipyretic_antics</file_name>
		<subject>Engineering_bewkve</subject>
		<oneline_desc>Extinguish your rivals' hopes of winning this event, as your mechanized creation puts out fires like a champ!</oneline_desc>
		<desc>
			<para>
				Test your grasp on the principles of engineering and optimization, as you build a boat which is capable of putting out multiple fires quickly and efficiently.
			</para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[<b>The problem statement is out! <a href="antipyretic_antics_problem_statement.pdf" target="_blank">Find it here.</a></b>]]>
			</para>
			<para><![CDATA[<b>Prizes worth Rs. 25000 at stake!</b>]]></para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[ <CENTER> <b> Co-ordinator: </b> <br>Amitabh Shrivastava<br> <a href="mailto:amitabh@pravega.org" target="_blank">amitabh@pravega.org</a></CENTER>]]>
			</para>	
		</desc>
		<image>porp.png</image>
		<rules_list>
			<rule>Aim is to put out all the fires as soon as possible, while going through obstacles.</rule>
			<rule>Teams can have a maximum of 4 members.</rule>
			<rule>Participants bring their own remote controlled boats.</rule>
			<rule>Pool will be <![CDATA[10ft &times; 8ft]]>, approximately 6 inches deep</rule>
			<rule>Boats will be tested on propulsion strength, manoeuvring and of course fire dowsing capabilities.</rule>
			<rule>There will be different fires of different types, but no liquid fuel based fires.</rule>
		</rules_list>
	</event>
	
	<event>
		<name>Chindogu Challenge</name>
		<file_name>chindogu_challenge</file_name>
		<subject>Engineering_blah</subject>
		<oneline_desc>Submit an invention which is wacky, avant-garde and completely un-useless!</oneline_desc>
		<desc>
			<para>
				"What's Chindogu?", you ask? Well, Wikipedia says: Chindogu is the Japanese art of inventing ingenious everyday gadgets that, on the face of it, seem like an ideal solution to a particular problem. However, Chindogu has a distinctive feature: anyone actually attempting to use one of these inventions would find that it causes so many new problems, or such significant social embarrassment, that effectively it has no utility whatsoever. Thus, Chindogu are sometimes described as "unuseless" - that is, they cannot be regarded as "useless" in an absolute sense, since they do actually solve a problem; however, in practical terms, they cannot positively be called "useful".
			</para>
			
			<para>
				Think inventing something useful is hard? Well, inventing something un-useless is harder still! Pravega challenges you to invent something wacky, cool and completely un-useless using any material that you can think of. Remember: the crazier, the wackier, the better!
			</para>
			
			<para>
				<![CDATA[Tip: Take a look here for inspiration: <a href="http://weburbanist.com/2013/06/26/chindogu-14-hilarious-and-strange-japanese-inventions/">http://weburbanist.com/2013/06/26/chindogu-14-hilarious-and-strange-japanese-inventions/</a>]]>
			</para>
			<para><![CDATA[<b>Prizes worth Rs. 10000 at stake!</b>]]></para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[ <CENTER> <b> Co-ordinator: </b> <br>Amitabh Shrivastava<br> <a href="mailto:amitabh@pravega.org" target="_blank">amitabh@pravega.org</a></CENTER>]]>
			</para>	
		</desc>
		<image>porp.png</image>
		<rules_list>
		</rules_list>
	</event>

	<event>
		<name>Gnidoc</name>
		<file_name>gnidoc</file_name>
		<subject>Engineering</subject>
		<oneline_desc>Reverse engineer the given executable and recode the programme from a top-down approach.</oneline_desc>
		<desc>
			<para>
				"Asking the right questions takes as much skill as giving the right answers" -Robert Half
			</para>
			
			<para>
				Gnidoc is programming turned on its head. Participants will be given a compiled executable to which they can give inputs and receive the corresponding inputs. Using only this, they will have to search for and identify patterns and write their own code to imitate the executable exactly. Remember: it's all about knowing how to ask the right questions!
			</para>
			<para><![CDATA[<b>Prizes worth Rs. 10000 at stake!</b>]]></para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[ <CENTER> <b> Co-ordinator: </b> <br>Pritish Patil<br> <a href="mailto:pritish@pravega.org" target="_blank">pritsh@pravega.org</a></CENTER>]]>
			</para>	
		</desc>
		<image>porp.png</image>
		<rules_list>
			<rule>Teams can have a maximum of 3 participants.</rule>
			<rule>There will be a written prelims, followed by finals to which 6 teams will qualify.</rule>
			<rule>You will be allowed to program in C, C++, an Java only.</rule>
		</rules_list>
	</event>

	<event>
		<name>Connect the Dots</name>
		<file_name>connect_the_dots</file_name>
		<subject>Engineering</subject>
		<oneline_desc>A computer science event where you race against time and follow a trail of clues to reach the final big puzzle.</oneline_desc>
		<desc>
			<para><![CDATA[<center><b>Event Sponsor: ABLabs Solutions</b></center>]]></para>
			<para>
				Connect the Dots is a Computer Science event. Each problem leads to another and the participants must follow the trail of clues to real the goal. The problems will test the participants on a variety of different concepts from computer science ranging from hashing to encryption. 
			</para>
			<para><![CDATA[<b>Prizes worth Rs. 10000 at stake!</b>]]></para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[ <CENTER> <b> Co-ordinator: </b> <br>Pritish Patil<br> <a href="mailto:pritish@pravega.org" target="_blank">pritsh@pravega.org</a></CENTER>]]>
			</para>	
		</desc>
		<image>porp.png</image>
		<rules_list>
			<rule>Teams can have a maximum of 3 participants.</rule>
			<rule>There will be a written prelims, followed by finals to which 6 teams will qualify.</rule>
			<rule>You will be allowed to program in C, C++, an Java only.</rule>
		</rules_list>
	</event>
	
	<event>
		<name>Pixel Pundit</name>
		<file_name>pixel_pundit</file_name>
		<subject>Engineering</subject>
		<oneline_desc>Show off your image processing skills to Carl Zeiss!</oneline_desc>
		<desc>
			<para>
				Image processing is a notoriously difficult job and an instigator of important computer science research today. That is exactly why Pravega, in partnership with Carl Zeiss, wants to find the best algorithms to do the job.
			</para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[
					<center><b>Impressive solutions will get an internship at Carl Zeiss. Final decision will be made by the company.</b></center>
				]]>
			</para>
			<para>
				It's up to you to show us that you have the talents in you!
			</para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[
				The problem statement pdf is available <a href="pixel_pundit_problem_statement.pdf" target="_blank">here</a>.<br>
				Image files are available here: <a href="zeiss_expert.zip">Expert</a> and <a href="zeiss_moderate.zip">Moderate</a>.
				]]>
			</para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[
				<center><b>The deadline is over. Thank you for participating!</b></center>
				]]>
			</para>
		</desc>
		<image>porp.png</image>
		<rules_list>
			<rule>There are two categories for participants: Students from Engineering disciplines and Students from Non-Engineering Participants.</rule>
			<rule>For each category, there are two levels: Level 1 (Moderate) for undergraduate participants, and Level 2 (Expert) for postgraduate and higher participants. Undergraduates may also try the Expert level, of course.</rule>
			<rule>
				<![CDATA[
				The problem statement pdf is available <a href="pixel_pundit_problem_statement.pdf" target="_blank">here</a>.<br>
				Image files are available here: <a href="zeiss_expert.zip">Expert</a> and <a href="zeiss_moderate.zip">Moderate</a>.
				]]>
			</rule>
			<rule>Participants are to mail their entries to <![CDATA[<a target="_blank" href="mailto:submissions@pravega.org?subject=Pixel Pundit Submission">submissions@pravega.org</a>]]> with subject "Pixel Pundit Submission" by the deadline of January 20th, 2014.</rule>
		</rules_list>	
	</event>
	
	<event>
		<name>Sukshm</name>
		<file_name>sukshm</file_name>
		<subject>Engineering</subject>
		<subject>Multi-Disciplinary</subject>
		<oneline_desc>A scanning electron microscopy competition from the experts of the field - Carl Zeiss!</oneline_desc>
		<desc>
			<para>
				Scanning electron microscopy is one of the most exciting applications of quantum mechanics, used by researchers around the world. Pravega and Zeiss now give you the opportunity to have your work appreciated by these researchers!
			</para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[
					<center><b>The best images will be featured in Carl Zeiss's calendar, which some of the most distinguished scientists across the world use.</b></center>
				]]>
			</para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[
				<center><b>Winners announced!</b></center><br>
					<ul style="margin-left: 25px;">
						<li>1st: Hareesh C (CeNSE, IISc) - "Cubism"</li>
						<li>2nd: Deepak Ranjan Nayak (CeNSE, IISc) - "Ge-Nanograss"</li>
						<li>3rd: K. S Vinay (Materials Engg, IISc) -"Superalloy Bouquet"</li>
						<li>4th: Ranjit Sai (CeNSE, IISc) - "World's best RF- inductor" and Khadija Khanum (Materials Engg, IISc) - "Bronze Age Weapons"</li>
					</ul>
				<b>Honourable Mentions:</b>
<ul style="margin-left: 25px;">
<li>6th: Vamsi Krishna (CeNSE, IISc, IISc)- "Micro-stadium"</li>
<li>7th: Krishna Rao Eswar (CeNSE, IISc- "United Broomsticks"</li>
<li>8th: Lavendra Yadav (CeNSE, IISc)- "Micro-mirrors"</li>
<li>9th: Clean room team (CeNSE, IISc)- "Micro-Battalion"</li>
<li>10th: <ol style="margin-left: 45px;">
<li>Khadija Khanum (Materials Engg, IISc)- "Open Heart"</li>
<li>Khadija Khanum (Materials Engg, IISc)- " Hilly Area Sunset"</li>
<li>Krishna Rao Eswar (CeNSE, IISc)- "Pit Falls"</li>
<li>Sangeeth Kallatt (CeNSE, IISc)- "Si- Nanograss"</li>
</ul></li></ul>
				
				
				
				]]>
			</para>
			
		</desc>
		<image>porp.png</image>
		<rules_list>
			<rule>No more than 2 entries from one person</rule>
			<rule>The image can be a single image or a combination of images. (original unprocessed images only) Use of false colour permitted. </rule>
			<rule>Details of the imaging conditions and technical details must be provided below the image. Magnification/micron marker/scale bars/detector (SE, BSE, etc.)/sample details must be indicated</rule>
			<rule>Each entry must be accompanied by an appropriate caption. The caption should not be descriptive, but instead be concise and catchy, and should tell a story.</rule>
			<rule>Please do not write your name/institution in the image. This should be indicated on the back side of the image. If the entry contains this information, the entry will be automatically disqualified.</rule>
			<rule>The maximum size of the entry will be A3 size paper. Entries have to be printed on glossy or matte or other high quality photo grade paper. Consider mounting your entry for aesthetic appeal (not required)</rule>
			<rule>Judging will take in to account the aesthetics as well as the technical quality of the image. </rule>
			<rule>Institute name and instrument (make and model) used should be mentioned. We will consider any EM (SEM, FE-SEM, FIB, HIM) images TEM images will not be considered.</rule>
			<rule>Only soft copies of the images along with complete contact details (Mobile number, email id) will be enough.</rule>
			<rule>Submit your entries to <![CDATA[<a href="mailto:submissions@pravega.org">submissions@pravega.org</a>]]>. The deadline is January 30th.</rule>
		</rules_list>	
	</event>
	
	<event>
		<name>Aerocarnival 2014 Finale</name>
		<file_name>aerocarnival</file_name>
		<subject>Engineering</subject>
		<oneline_desc>The Aerocarnival grand finale, to be held here at IISc!</oneline_desc>
		<desc>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[<a href="http://www.avianworkshops.com/carnival.html">Aerocarnival</a>]]> will be holding its grand finale at Pravega - where zonal finalists will compete for the ultimate prize!
			</para>
			<para>
				Aero Carnival is a national level multi-disciplinary training program cum competition on unmanned systems technology and model rocketry.
			</para>
			<para>
				This event is aimed at bringing awareness about unmanned systems and model rocketry, its importance and applications amongst the Indian students. The uniqueness about unmanned systems is that it involves technology from various branches of engineering. Hence the workshops is suitable for students from  various engineering disciplines like Aero, Auto, Mech, EEE, ECE, E<![CDATA[&I]]> etc. The event has multiple events to choose from. The students will participate in the training program in their college where the top performing teams will be selected and they get to participate at the Aerocarnival grand finale to be held at Pravega '14 at IISc, Bangalore.
			</para>
			<para>
				We call up on the students and management of all engineering colleges to become a part of this tech extravaganza and make this event a grand success!
			</para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[
					To become Zonal centers or participate in an event, please contact<br>
					Phone: +91 9445508328<br>
					Email: <a href="mailto:carnival@avianaerospace.com" target="_blank">carnival@avianaerospace.com</a>
				]]>
			</para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[The four final competitions will be:
				<ul style="margin-left:30px; margin-top:-30px;">
					<li>Flapping MAV</li>
					<li>Model Rocketry</li>
					<li>Air Cushion Vehicle</li>
					<li>Fixed Wing UAV</li>
				</ul>]]>		
			</para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[<b>This event will not be open for general registration.</b>]]>
			</para>
		</desc>
		<image>aerocarnival.png</image>
		<rules_list>
			
		</rules_list>
	</event>
	
	<event>
		<name>Mobile Making Workshop</name>
		<file_name>mobile_making</file_name>
		<subject>Workshops</subject>
		<oneline_desc>Learn to build a mobile phone!</oneline_desc>
		<desc>
			<para><![CDATA[<center><b>Seats are limited. Register now!</b></center>]]></para>
			<para>
			<![CDATA[
			<table>
				<tr style="margin-bottom:10px;">
					<td style="padding:0px; padding-right:20px; text-align:right; vertical-align:top;"><b>Date:</b></td>
					<td style="padding:0px;">January 31&ndash;February 1, 2014</td>
				</tr>
				<tr style="margin-bottom:10px;">
					<td style="padding:0px; padding-right:20px; text-align:right; vertical-align:top;"><b>Duration:</b></td>
					<td style="padding:0px;"> 16 hours over 2 days with both theory and practical sessions.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr style="margin-bottom:10px;">
					<td style="padding:0px; padding-right:20px; text-align:right; vertical-align:top;"><b>Venue:</b></td>
					<td style="padding:0px;"> IISc Bangalore</td>
				</tr>
				<tr style="margin-bottom:10px;">
					<td style="padding:0px; padding-right:20px; width:13em; text-align:right; vertical-align:top;"><b>Cost of the workshop:</b></td>
					<td style="padding:0px;"> Rs. 5000/- per team. The maximum team size is 4. This does not include the kit, which can be purchased <b>on-spot</b> for Rs. 2500.<br>Individuals can also register for Rs. 1300.</td>
				</tr>
			</table>
			<p>
				<CENTER> <b> Co-ordinator: </b> <br>Mukund Seethamraju<br> <a href="mailto:mukund@pravega.org" target="_blank">mukund@pravega.org</a></CENTER>
			</p>	
			<p style="text-align:center;">
				<b>Sorry, this event has reached its capacity and is no longer accepting registrations. There will be no spot registrations.</b>
			</p>
			]]>
			</para>
			
			<para>
				<![CDATA[
				<h3>Course Outline:</h3>
				<ul style="margin-left:40px;">
					<li>Introduction to Embedded Systems</li>
					<li>Application of Embedded Systems</li>
					<li>Overview of Basic Electronics</li>
					<li>Overview of Digital Electronics</li>
					<li>AVR Software Tools &ndash; AVR Studio, WinAVR, SinaProg</li>
					<li>Introduction to ATmega16</li>
					<li>Features of ATmega16</li>
					<li>I/O Ports of ATmega16</li>
					<li>LED Interfacing with ATmega16</li>
					<li>DIfferent LED Pattern Generation</li>
					<li>4&times;4 Keypad Interfacing with ATmega16</li>
					<li>16&times;2 Alphanumeric LCD Interfacing with ATmega16</li>
					<li>Horizontal Scrolling in 16&times;2 Alphanumeric LCD</li>
					<li>Vertical Scrolling in 16&times;2 Alphanumeric LCD</li>
					<li>USART</li>
					<li>USART of ATmega16</li>
					<li>GSM Communciation</li>
					<li>AT Command</li>
					<li>SIM 300 GSM/GPRS Modem Interfacing with ATmega16</li>
					<li>SIM Card Detection in SIM 300 GSM/GPRS Modem</li>
					<li>SMS Reading from SIM 300 GSM/GPRS Modem with ATmega16</li>
					<li>SMS Sending from SIM 300 GSM/GPRS Modem with ATmega16</li>
					<li>Calling from SIM 300 GSM/GPRS Modem with ATmega16</li>
					<li>Call Receiving from SIM 300 GSM/GPRS Modem with ATmega16</li>
					<li>Calling Line Identification</li>
				</ul>
				]]>
			</para>
			<para>
				Content developed in association with ABLab Solutions, Bhubaneswar.
			</para>
		</desc>
		<image>logos/mobile_building.jpg</image>
	</event>
	
	<event>
		<name>CAN Sat Workshop</name>
		<file_name>satellite</file_name>
		<subject>Workshops</subject>
		<oneline_desc>Design and launch a satellite!</oneline_desc>
		<desc>
			<para>
			<![CDATA[
			<table>
				<tr style="margin-bottom:10px;">
					<td style="padding:0px; padding-right:20px; text-align:right; vertical-align:top;"><b>Date:</b></td>
					<td style="padding:0px;">January 31&ndash;February 1, 2014</td>
				</tr>
				<tr style="margin-bottom:10px;">
					<td style="padding:0px; padding-right:20px; text-align:right; vertical-align:top;"><b>Duration:</b></td>
					<td style="padding:0px;"> 16 hours over 2 days with both theory and practical sessions.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr style="margin-bottom:10px;">
					<td style="padding:0px; padding-right:20px; text-align:right; vertical-align:top;"><b>Venue:</b></td>
					<td style="padding:0px;"> IISc Bangalore</td>
				</tr>
				<tr style="margin-bottom:10px;">
					<td style="padding:0px; padding-right:20px; width:13em; text-align:right; vertical-align:top;"><b>Cost of the workshop:</b></td>
					<td style="padding:0px;">Rs. 1000/- per participant. Participants will be incorporated in a team if they do not have their own.</td>
				</tr>

			</table>
			<p>
				<CENTER> <b> Co-ordinator: </b> <br>Kishalay De<br> <a href="mailto:kishalay@pravega.org" target="_blank">kishalay@pravega.org</a></CENTER>
			</p>
			<p style="text-align:center;">
				<b>Sorry, this event has reached its capacity and is no longer accepting registrations. There will be no spot registrations.</b>
			</p>
			<br>
			]]>
			</para>
			
			<para>
				<![CDATA[
				<h3>Course Outline:</h3>
				Individual team members will work parallely in the following areas:
				<ul style="margin-left:40px;">
					<li>Mechanical Testing</li>
					<li>Breadboard and Circuit Design</li>
					<li>Soldering the circuits</li>
					<li>Programming the firmware</li>
					<li>Integration, and testing of data</li>
				</ul>
				]]>
			</para>
			<para>
				The second day's session will be spent launching the satellites. There will also be a post-flight review given by each team-member, describing their results, with a focus on robustness, functionality, results, analysis of performance, and time management.
			</para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[<b><u>FAQ</u></b><br>]]>
			</para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[<b>What are the prerequisites for the workshop?</b><br>]]>
				During workshop, we will start from the basics till the implementation of CAN Satellite. In addition, first one or two sessions may involve theoretical discussion( about kit development, sensors, hardware install, software and so on.). So, one can easily grab everything. 
			</para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[<b>Who can enrol?</b><br>]]>
				Students beyond 9th standard can enrol for the workshop.
			</para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[<b>What is the objective of the workshop?</b><br>]]>
				The objective of CAN Satellite is to conceptualize, design, build, test a small mock satellite. We use parachutes in order to launch the CAN Satellite. After launching, we will note down the various data sensed by the satellite.
				<![CDATA[<br><br>]]>
				It is not possible to set up satellite in orbit since that requires permission from governmental bodies. Also, the budget of a real satellite is in the range of several crore rupees.
			</para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[<b>What is the timing of the workshop?</b><br>]]>
				Registration and other formalities starts at 09:00 AM.
			</para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[<b>Q. What about team?</b><br>]]>
				Each team consists of 5 members. Participants will be incorporated in a team if they do not have their own.
			</para>
		</desc>
		<image>events/satellite.png</image>
	</event>
	
	<event>
		<name>RC Cars Workshop</name>
		<file_name>rc_cars</file_name>
		<subject>Workshops</subject>
		<oneline_desc>Build a radio controlled car!</oneline_desc>
		<desc>
			<para>
			<![CDATA[
			<table>
				<tr style="margin-bottom:10px;">
					<td style="padding:0px; padding-right:20px; text-align:right; vertical-align:top;"><b>Date:</b></td>
					<td style="padding:0px;">31st January&ndash;1st Feburary</td>
				</tr>
				<tr style="margin-bottom:10px;">
					<td style="padding:0px; padding-right:20px; text-align:right; vertical-align:top;"><b>Duration:</b></td>
					<td style="padding:0px;">13-16 hours in 5 sessions over 2 days with both theory and practical components.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr style="margin-bottom:10px;">
					<td style="padding:0px; padding-right:20px; text-align:right; vertical-align:top;"><b>Venue:</b></td>
					<td style="padding:0px;"> IISc Bangalore</td>
				</tr>
				<tr style="margin-bottom:10px;">
					<td style="padding:0px; padding-right:20px; width:13em; text-align:right; vertical-align:top;"><b>Cost of the workshop:</b></td>
					<td style="padding:0px;"> Rs. 950/- per participant. Every participant will get one software package & EISystems LifeCard.</td>
				</tr>
			</table>
			<p>
				<CENTER> <b> Co-ordinator: </b> <br>Ananthesh Sundaresh<br> <a href="mailto:ananthesh@pravega.org" target="_blank">ananthesh@pravega.org</a></CENTER>
			</p>
			<p style="text-align:center;">
				<b>Sorry, this event has reached its capacity and is no longer accepting registrations. There will be no spot registrations.</b>
			</p>
			<br>
			]]>
			</para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[
					<h3>Eligibility Criteria</h3>
						This is a basic level workshop, so the prerequiste required will be zero.<br>
						The workshop will be beneficial for participants from Mechanical, Production, Designing, Automobiles or Electronics background with interest in automobiles.
				]]>
			</para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[
					<h3>Certification Policy</h3>
						Certificate of Participation for all the workshop participants from EISystems & Pravega IISc Bangalore.
				]]>
			</para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[
					<h3>Workshop Material Deliverables</h3>
						<ol style="margin-left:45px;">
							<li>Certificate of Participation as per certification policy.</li>
							<li>Software Compact Disk with material related to workshop.</li>
							<li>EISystems LifeID for internships & further buyings</li>
						</ol>
						Please note that no RC Car will be provided as material deliverable either in group or as an individual.
				]]>
			</para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[
					<h3>Workshop Content</h3>
				]]>
			</para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[
					<b>Session 1:</b>
					<ol style="margin-top:-25px; margin-left:40px;">
						<li>
							<b>Introduction to Automobiles</b>
							<ul style="margin-left:45px;">
								<li>What are automobiles?</li>
								<li>History of automobiles</li>
								<li>Importance of automobiles to humankind</li>
								<li>Future of automobiles</li>
							</ul>
						</li>
						<li>
							<b>Introduction to radio controlled cars</b>
							<ul style="margin-left:45px;">
								<li>What a RC Car is</li>
								<li>Origin of RC cars</li>
								<li>Advantages of RC cars</li>
								<li>Applications of RC cars</li>
							</ul>
						</li>
						<li>
							<b>Types of radio controlled cars</b>
							<ul style="margin-left:45px;">
								<li>Different types of RC Cars</li>
								<li>Petrol RC Car</li>
								<li>Nitro RC Car</li>
								<li>Electric RC Car</li>
							</ul>
						</li>
					</ol>
				]]>
			</para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[
					<b>Session 2:</b>
					<ol style="margin-top:-25px; margin-left:40px;">
						<li>
							<b>Components of Radio controlled cars (overview)</b>
							<ul style="margin-left:45px;">
								<li>Various components of RC cars</li>
								<li>Engine</li>
								<li>Differential</li>
								<li>Gearbox</li>
								<li>Carburetor</li>
								<li>Suspension</li>
								<li>Steering</li>
								<li>Servo Motor</li>
								<li>Transmitter</li>
								<li>Receiver</li>
							</ul>
						</li>
					</ol>
				]]>
			</para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[
					<b>Session 3:</b>
					<ol style="margin-top:-25px; margin-left:40px;">
						<li>
							<b>Hands-on session (for individual groups)<br>Detailed explanation on working of components (for individual groups)</b>
							<ul style="margin-left:45px;">
								<li>Engine</li>
								<li>Differential</li>
								<li>Gearbox</li>
								<li>Carburetor</li>
								<li>Suspension</li>
								<li>Steering</li>
								<li>Servo Motor</li>
								<li>Transmitter</li>
								<li>Receiver</li>
							</ul>
						</li>
					</ol>
				]]>
			</para>
			<para>
			<![CDATA[
				RC project ideas and games<br>
				Various competitions held at IITB, BITS PILANI, RCINC and international competitions.<br>
				Guidelines of Competitions<br>
				Eligibility of Competitions<br>
				Various advancements and project ideas for competitions<br><br>
				<b>Project Work:</b><br>
				Design an Innovative Type of Radio Control Car for real life applications
				<ol style="margin-top:-25px; margin-left:40px;">
					<li>It can be either drawn with free hand Sketch with Description of the Product or</li>
					<li>It can be modeled in any CAD software with description of the Component.</li>
				</ol>
				(Additional credit to be given)
			]]>
			</para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[
					<b>Session 4:</b>
					<ol style="margin-top:-25px; margin-left:40px;">
						<li>
							<b>Details on components to be fabricated</b>
							<ul style="margin-left:45px;">
								<li>Various Modifications in chassis</li>
								<li>Knuckle</li>
								<li>Wishbone</li>
								<li>Steering Joints</li>
								<li>Rollcage</li>
								<li>Steering rods</li>
								<li>Ball joints</li>
							</ul>
						</li>
						
						<li>
							<b>Basic Tuning Procedures</b>
							<ul style="margin-left:45px;">
								<li>Concept of Air Fuel Mixture</li>
								<li>Rich Mixture</li>
								<li>Lean Mixture</li>
								<li>Normal Mixture</li>
							</ul>
						</li>
						<li>
							<b>Racing Techniques</b>
						</li>
					</ol>
				]]>
			</para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[
					<b>Session 5:</b>
					<ol style="margin-top:-25px; margin-left:40px;">
						<li>Innovations in RC cars.</li>
						<li>Essential Checks before and after running your RC car.</li>
						<li>RC car Quiz for all the participants.</li>
						<li>How to control RC cars on track.</li>
						<li>Basic Stunt show on RC car</li>
					</ol>
				]]>
			</para>
		</desc>
		<image>logos/rc_cars.png</image>
	</event>
	
	<event>
		<name>Flying Machine Nano Workshop</name>
		<file_name>flying_machine_nano</file_name>
		<subject>Workshops</subject>
		<oneline_desc>Build a quadcopter!</oneline_desc>
		<desc>
			<para>
			<![CDATA[
			<table>
				<tr style="margin-bottom:10px;">
					<td style="padding:0px; padding-right:20px; text-align:right; vertical-align:top;"><b>Date:</b></td>
					<td style="padding:0px;">January 31&ndash;February 1, 2014</td>
				</tr>
				<tr style="margin-bottom:10px;">
					<td style="padding:0px; padding-right:20px; text-align:right; vertical-align:top;"><b>Duration:</b></td>
					<td style="padding:0px;">16 hours over 2 days.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr style="margin-bottom:10px;">
					<td style="padding:0px; padding-right:20px; text-align:right; vertical-align:top;"><b>Venue:</b></td>
					<td style="padding:0px;"> IISc Bangalore</td>
				</tr>
				<tr style="margin-bottom:10px;">
					<td style="padding:0px; padding-right:20px; width:13em; text-align:right; vertical-align:top;"><b>Cost of the workshop:</b></td>
					<td style="padding:0px;">Rs. 7000/- for a team of 5.</td>
				</tr>
			</table>
			<p>
				<CENTER> <b> Co-ordinator: </b> <br>Amlan Das<br> <a href="mailto:amlan@pravega.org" target="_blank">amlan@pravega.org</a></CENTER>
			</p>
			<p style="text-align:center;">
				<b>Sorry, this event has reached its capacity and is no longer accepting registrations. There will be no spot registrations.</b>
			</p>
			<br>
			]]>
			</para>
			
			<para>
				<![CDATA[
				<h3>Brief Description:</h3>
				A necessary experience for any aerodynamics enthusiast! The highlights of the workshop include:
				<ul style="margin-left:40px;">
					<li>Introduction to Aerodynamics
					<li>Vertical Take of and Landing Explained</li>
					<li>Control Systems</li>
					<li>Remote-Control systems</li>
					<li>Mechanical Structure</li>
					<li>Quad-copter construction and Flight</li>
				</ul>
				]]>
			</para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[
				<h3>Course Outline:</h3>
				<ul style="margin-left:40px;">
					<li><b>Introduction to Aerodynamics:</b>
						<ul style="margin-left:60px;">
							<li>What is Aerodynamics</li>
							<li>Introduction to different kinds of aerial vehicles</li>
							<li>Different kind of take off and landing techniques</li>
							<li>Working of Different kind of Aerial vehicles</li>
						</ul>
					</li>
					<li><b>Concept of VTOL (Vertical Liftoff and Landing):</b>
						<ul style="margin-left:60px;">
							<li>Why VTOL</li>
							<li>Multi rotor platforms and VTOL</li>
							<li>Drawbacks of Multi rotor platforms</li>
							<li>How to overcome the drawbacks using Control systems</li>
						</ul>
					</li>
					<li><b>Control Systems in Multi rotor platforms:</b>
						<ul style="margin-left:60px;">
							<li>Technical details of the control system used</li>
						</ul>
					</li>
					<li><b>Introduction to RC Systems:</b>
						<ul style="margin-left:60px;">
							<li>Types of Radios(Rx/Tx)</li>
							<li>Types of signals and their pros and cons.</li>
						</ul>
					</li>
					<li><b>Mechanical Structures:</b>
						<ul style="margin-left:60px;">					
							<li>Various Motor and ESCs</li>
							<li>Propellers</li>
						</ul>
					</li>
					<li><b>Construction of Quadcopter</b>
						<ul style="margin-left:60px;">		
							<li>Construction of Fuselage</li>
							<li>Understanding the Role of Microcontroller</li>
							<li>Adding Sensors for balancing of the QuadCopter</li>
							<li>Adding electronics</li>
							<li>Tuning the system</li>
							<li>Programming Various Flight Mode.</li>
						</ul>
					</li>
					<li><b>Flying the Quadcopter:</b>
						<ul style="margin-left:60px;">		
							<li>Final tests and flight</li>
						</ul>
					</li>
				</ul>
				]]>
			</para>
		</desc>
		<image>events/flying_machine_nano.jpg</image>
	</event>
	
	<event>
		<name>Gesture Game Development Workshop</name>
		<file_name>ggd_workshop</file_name>
		<subject>Workshops</subject>
		<oneline_desc></oneline_desc>
		<desc>
			<para>
			<![CDATA[
			<table>
				<tr style="margin-bottom:10px;">
					<td style="padding:0px; padding-right:20px; text-align:right; vertical-align:top;"><b>Date:</b></td>
					<td style="padding:0px;">January 31&ndash;February 1, 2014</td>
				</tr>
				<tr style="margin-bottom:10px;">
					<td style="padding:0px; padding-right:20px; text-align:right; vertical-align:top;"><b>Duration:</b></td>
					<td style="padding:0px;"> 14 hours over 4 sessions of 3.5 hours each.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr style="margin-bottom:10px;">
					<td style="padding:0px; padding-right:20px; text-align:right; vertical-align:top;"><b>Venue:</b></td>
					<td style="padding:0px;"> IISc Bangalore</td>
				</tr>
				<tr style="margin-bottom:10px;">
					<td style="padding:0px; padding-right:20px; width:13em; text-align:right; vertical-align:top;"><b>Cost of the workshop:</b></td>
					<td style="padding:0px;">Rs. 1000/- per participant</td>
				</tr>
			</table>
			
			<p>
				<CENTER> <b> Co-ordinator: </b> <br>Abhishek Balakrishna<br> <a href="mailto:abhishek@pravega.org" target="_blank">abhishek@pravega.org</a></CENTER>
			</p>
			<p style="text-align:center;">
				<b>Sorry, this event has reached its capacity and is no longer accepting registrations. There will be no spot registrations.</b>
			</p>
			<br>
			]]>
			</para>
			
			<para>
				<![CDATA[
				<h3>Brief Description:</h3>
				Here are some of the workshop highlights:
				<ul style="margin-left:40px;">
					<li>Introduction to Gesture Game Development
					<li>Using Vision Algorithms for controlling computer mice and keyboards</li>
					<li>Using Vision Algorithms for playing computer games</li>
					<li>Overview of current research in this field</li>
				</ul><br>
				<iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/Sb9pyKr9Gp0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
				]]>
			</para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[
				<h3>Course Outline</h3>
				Below is a detailed description of the workshop's components:
				<ul style="margin-left:40px;">
					<li>Introduction To Gesture Game Development
					<li>Introduction to MATLAB</li>
					<li>Digital Image Processing using MATLAB</li>
					<li>Gesture controlled mouse</li>
					<li>Gesture controlled keyboard</li>
					<li>Playing water surfing games using gestures</li>
					<li>Playing shooting games using gestures</li>
					<li>Playing Boxing games using gestures</li>
					<li>Playing Kick boxing games using gestures </li>
					<li>Playing skiing games using gestures</li>
					<li>Playing Bike racing Games using gestures</li>
					<li>Playing games on miniclip using gestures</li>
					<li>Playing track and field games using gestures</li>
					<li>Playing cricket using gestures</li>
					<li>Playing bowling using gestures</li>
					<li>Playing car racing games using gestures</li>
					<li>Overview of ongoing research in the field of Gesture Game Development</li>
				</ul>
				]]>
			</para>
			<para>This workshop is being conducted by Robofission Labs Pvt. Ltd.</para>
		</desc>
		<image>events/ggd_workshop.jpg</image>
	</event>
	
	<event>
		<name>Cloud Computing <![CDATA[&]]> Google App Engine Workshop</name>
		<file_name>cloud_computing_workshop</file_name>
		<subject>Workshops</subject>
		<oneline_desc>Learn to harness the cloud!</oneline_desc>
		<desc>
			<para>
			<![CDATA[
			 <b>Spot registratios are open for Cloud Computing Workshop!<br>Batch 1: 12pm, 31st Jan - 1st Feb.<br>Batch 2: Feb 1st and Feb 2nd</b>
			<table>
				<tr style="margin-bottom:10px;">
					<td style="padding:0px; padding-right:20px; text-align:right; vertical-align:top;"><b>Date:</b></td>
					<td style="padding:0px;">January 31&ndash;February 1, 2014</td>
				</tr>
				<tr style="margin-bottom:10px;">
					<td style="padding:0px; padding-right:20px; text-align:right; vertical-align:top;"><b>Duration:</b></td>
					<td style="padding:0px;">2 day workshop - including lectures, discussions, demonstration, and practical sessions.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr style="margin-bottom:10px;">
					<td style="padding:0px; padding-right:20px; text-align:right; vertical-align:top;"><b>Venue:</b></td>
					<td style="padding:0px;"> IISc Bangalore</td>
				</tr>
				<tr style="margin-bottom:10px;">
					<td style="padding:0px; padding-right:20px; width:13em; text-align:right; vertical-align:top;"><b>Cost of the workshop:</b></td>
					<td style="padding:0px;">Rs. 1200/- per participant</td>
				</tr>
				<tr style="margin-bottom:10px;">
					<td colspan="2" style="padding:0px; padding-right:20px; vertical-align:top; text-align:center; padding-top:10px;"><b>Participants are advised to bring their own laptops.</b></td>
				</tr>
			</table>
			<p>
				<CENTER> <b> Co-ordinator: </b> <br>Rohit Chatterjee<br> <a href="mailto:rohitc@pravega.org" target="_blank">rohitc@pravega.org</a> / <a href="mailto:ugcrohit@ug.iisc.in" target="_blank">ugcrohit@ug.iisc.in</a></CENTER>
			</p>
			<p style="text-align:center;">
				<a href="" class="button button-style1" onclick="$.scrollTo('#register', 400, {offset:-25}, {easing:'swing'}); return false;">Register now!</a>
				<br><br>
				After registering, please go <a target="_blank" href="http://em.explara.com/event/pravega-workshops">here</a> and select the Cloud Computing Workshop ticket for payment.
			</p>
			<br>
			]]>
			</para>
			
			<para>
				<![CDATA[
				<h3>Brief Description:</h3>
				Here are some of the workshop highlights:
				<ul style="margin-left:40px;">
					<li>Lectures on Cloud Computing - Introduction, characterization, Google App Engine</li>
					<li>Different Cloud computing architectures</li>
					<li>Group Discussions as well as multimedia demonstrations</li>
				</ul>
				]]>
			</para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[
				<h3>Course Outline</h3>
				Below is a detailed description of the workshop's components:
				<ul style="margin-left:40px;">
					<li>Introduction to Cloud Computing</li>
					<li>Characteristics of Cloud Computing</li>
					<li>Advantages & Disadvantages of Cloud Computing</li>
					<li>SaaS, PaaS, IaaS</li>
					<li>Understanding Cloud Security</li>
					<li>Understanding Services and Applications</li>
					<li>Understanding Google App Engine</li>
					<li>Developing Applications on GAE</li>
					<li>Backends: Datastore, Memcache, OAuth, XMPP, Frameworks</li>
					<li>Using APIs for different vendors</li>
					<li>Live demonstration and examples</li>
				</ul>
				]]>
			</para>
			<para>This workshop is being conducted by IIT Kanpur graduates from Code Instruct.</para>
		</desc>
		<image>events/cloud_computing.png</image>
	</event>
	
	<event>
		<name>EI Systems Mechfest</name>
		<file_name>mechfest</file_name>
		<subject></subject>
		<oneline_desc></oneline_desc>
		<desc>
			<para>
				It gives us great pleasure to introduce Mechfest, a national level workshop and competition series based on automobile technology. The Mechfest is sponsored and funded by India's biggest automobiles, information and communication technology training company, EISystems Services. 
			</para>
			
			<para>
				MechFEST will bring students from all over the country together to participate in the celebration of knowledge and creative extravagance along with experts from the fields of academia as well as industry. It hosts various challenging events based on automobile technology concepts. The list of them is given below:
			</para>
			
			<para>
			<![CDATA[
			<ul style="margin-left:75px;">
				<li>Automobile Mechanics & IC Engine Design</li>
				<li>Automobile Manufacturing Processes</li>
				<li>Remote Controlled Cars</li>
			</ul>
			]]>
			</para>

			<para>
				With technological innovation scaling new heights, Mechfest promises to keep a tab on the advancements and stay in sync with the mood of the times. With the introduction of several new events and workshop modules, Mechfest is all set to create a new benchmark. This time Mechfest will be organized by Pravega 2014 in association with our official partner EISystems Services. 
			</para>
			
			<para>
				We are organizing zonal Rounds of Mechfest in around 30 campuses across India. Hoping we will be there at your college!
			</para>
			
			<para>
				To the organize Mechfest Workshop <![CDATA[&]]> Competition in your college, please contact the below person:
			</para>
			
			<para>
			<![CDATA[
				Mayur Dev Sewak<br>
				General Manager, MechFest Outreach<br>
				+91 9761118111 | +91 9212251000<br>
				<b><a href="http://www.mechfest.org" target="_blank">www.mechfest.org</a><br>
				<a href="mailto:mayursewak@mechfest.org" target="_blank">mayursewak@mechfest.org</a></b>
			]]>
			</para>
		</desc>
		<image></image>
	</event>
	
	<event>
		<name>Swissnex Science Slam</name>
		<file_name>science_slam</file_name>
		<subject>Multi-Disciplinary</subject>
		<oneline_desc>Present your research in a fun and entertaining way in 3 minutes flat!</oneline_desc>
		<desc>
			<para>
			<![CDATA[
				<b>First Prize</b><br>]]>
				Trip to Switzerland! The core ideator of the invention/project gets to visit a Swiss University. swissnex will provide Return Airfare and Accommodation for 2 nights and three days and the per diem allowance.
			</para>
			<para>
			<![CDATA[
				<b>Second Prize</b><br>]]>
				1 Swatch watch
			</para>
			<para>
			<![CDATA[
				<b>Third Prize</b><br>]]>
				1 Swiss Military Bag + Goodies
			</para>
			<para>
			<![CDATA[
				<b>For all participants</b><br>]]>
				All the registered participants will receive Goodie Bags with Swiss Chocolates and Lunch Coupons worth Rs. 200 from IISc Food Court on the event day.
			</para>
		</desc>
		<image>porp.png</image>
		<rules_list>
			<rule>Submissions close on 15th January, 2014.</rule>
			<rule>Registration must be done here as well as through the submission to Swissnex.</rule>
			<rule>A single team member must register here. Sub team members if any can be mentioned in the submission.</rule>
			<rule>Open to undergraduates, masters, and PhD students.</rule>
			<rule><![CDATA[Please refer to the <a href="science_slam.pdf" target="_blank">guidelines document</a> for the complete rules and submission details.]]></rule>
			<rule><![CDATA[The URL to submit details of your research and performance is <a href="http://svy.mk/1b4MpNG" target="_blank">svy.mk/1b4MpNG</a>.]]></rule>
		</rules_list>
	</event>
	
	<event>
		<name>Treasure Hunt</name>
		<file_name>treasure_hunt</file_name>
		<subject>Multi-Disciplinary</subject>
		<oneline_desc>A frenetic chase to discover hidden clues and recover the treasure.</oneline_desc>
		<desc>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[
				<center><b>
					The online registration closes at 28th midnight. We are accepting on-spot registration for Treasure Hunt from 9 am to 12 pm on Friday, January 31st and 9-10:30 am Saturday, February 1st at Tata Memorial Club (TMC) on both days due to large number of online participants.
				</b></center>
				]]>
			</para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[
					<b><center>
						Prelims clue will be sent by mail and text message between 11:15 - 11:30. If not yet received by 11:30, contact the following at the main building.<br>
						Hemaa S - 9448173998
					</center></b>
				]]>
			</para>
			<para>The 443 acre lush green campus of IISc is a nature lover's delight. Despite being situated bang in the middle of urban Bengaluru, the thickly foliated campus is a haven of greenery and peace; it harbours over 300 species of plants and 140 species of birds. Sounds like heaven?</para>
			<para>Team Pravega will scatter a bunch of clues across the across the beautiful campus for this event. Each clue will direct you to the next. Clues will encompass a wide variety of fields - from popular culture to technology to sports. And they will all come together in the end to reveal the overarching theme - a puzzle within the puzzles. And the treasure awaits those who manage to crack that!</para>
			<para>Are you nimble of both feet and mind? What are you waiting for? Register for the Pravega Treasure Hunt!</para>
		</desc>
		<image>events/treasure_hunt.jpg</image>
		<rules_list>
			<rule>Online Registration is open till January 28th. Spot registration will be open from 9 am to 12 pm on Friday, January 31st and 9-10:30 am Saturday, February 1st at the Tata Memorial Club (TMC) on both days.</rule>
			<rule>There are two stages in the event - The Prelims is open to all and the top 10 teams at the end of Prelims will participate in the final hunt for the treasure. (A maximum of 3 teams from the same institution will be allowed to participate in the final hunt for the treasure).</rule>
			<rule>
				<![CDATA[
				<b>Prelims Rules</b>
				<ol style="margin-left:30px;">
					<li>A team of three (minimum) to five (maximum) can participate.</li>
					<li>During the online registration, the team should provide two mobile numbers per team, which they will be carrying during the event. This will enable them to receive the prelims' clue via sms. The clue will also be sent by email to all participants</li>
					<li>Since speed is of essence, the team members are allowed to split up to crack the clue during the Prelims.</li>
					<li>The use of mobile phones is allowed for the communicating between the team members only and for the use of internet (which is recommended) (No laptops/tablets are allowed).</li>
					<li>You are not allowed to seek any kind of external help during the hunt.</li>
					<li>During the hunt, use of foot alone is permitted. Anyone found violating this, will be disqualified.</li>
				</ol>
				]]>
			</rule>
			<rule>Both prelims and finals will be held on the second day of Pravega, i.e. February 1st. There will be a one hour break after prelims for lunch before the finals begin for the selected teams.</rule>
			<rule>
				<![CDATA[
				<b>Finals Rules</b>
				<ol style="margin-left:30px;">
					<li>The first 10 teams after the Prelims, qualify for finals and will be provided cycles for commuting from point-to-point in the finals.</li>
					<li>From this point on, the team members may split up for searching for the clue, but all the team members have to be present when collecting a clue.</li>
					<li>Each team will get a different route to the treasure, so no team will get the same route and the sequence will be checked at the end point (If the sequence of clues does not match with those given by the organizers, the team will be disqualified).</li>
				</ol>
				]]>
			</rule>
		</rules_list>
	</event>
	
	
	<event>
		<name>Idea Within: Paper Presentation</name>
		<file_name>paper_presentation</file_name>
		<subject>Multi-Disciplinary</subject>
		<subject>Engineering</subject>
		<oneline_desc>Present your research to the world!</oneline_desc>
		<desc>
			<para>
				Pravega invites papers from students on topics from all engineering streams.
			</para>
			<para>At Pravega, we are looking for freshness in ideas. Ingenuity, imagination and originality are the factors by which your papers will be judged - not by technicality or jargon. Present your work before some of the most renowned researchers in the field and walk away with prizes!</para>
			<para>Last day for abstract submission is <![CDATA[<b>January 10th, 2014</b>]]>. Shortlisted participants will  be called to give an oral presentation of their paper at IISc Bangalore during Pravega 2014.</para>
			<para>Winners have been declared below! Congratulations!</para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[
				<ul style="margin-left: 50px;">
					<li>1st - Theja Ram Pingali, Anurag Shivprasad, Sarthak Dubey, Arpit Varshney - R.V. College of Engineering, Bangalore, Karnataka</li>
					<li>2nd - Aravinth K, Logeshwaran M - Kongu Engineering College, Erode, Tamilnadu</li>
					<li>3rd - Shruti Bhandakkar, Roshni Pradeep, Varsha Pawar - Fr. Conceicao Rodrigues College of Engineering, Mumbai, Maharashtra</li>
				</ul>
				]]>
			</para>
			<para>Participants can contact Mayukh Nath (email: mayukh.nath.san@gmail.com, mobile number: 9611327706) for any further queries.</para>
		</desc>
		<image>porp.png</image>
		<rules_list>
			<rule>This is a team based competition with a maximum of 5 members per team. Individual entries are also allowed.</rule>
			<rule>
				<![CDATA[<b>Abstract submission:</b><br>
				An abstract must be submitted online which should concisely define the theme of the paper. Word limit is 200 words. Please mail your abstracts to <a href="mailto:suhas@pravega.org">suhas@pravega.org</a>
				<br>Last date for abstract submission is January 10th, 2014. Shortlisted participants will be announced by January 12th 2014.]]>
			</rule>
			<rule>
				<![CDATA[<b>Finals:</b>
				<ul style="margin-left:25px;">
					<li>Shortlisted teams will have to come to IISc Bangalore for the finals during Pravega 2014</li>
					<li>Shortlisted teams will have to confirm within 7 days their participation in the finals.</li>
					<li>Participants are permitted to use slideshows for the presentation.</li>
					<li>10 minutes will be allotted per paper and 5 minutes for question answer.</li>
					<li>Recorded dialogues/ movie clippings are not allowed.</li>
					<li>Multiple papers can be submitted by an individual.</li>
					<li>Decision of judges is final and binding.</li>
				</ul>]]>
			</rule>
		</rules_list>
	</event>
	
	<event>
		<name>Idea Within: Mass Transportation</name>
		<file_name>iw_mass_transportation</file_name>
		<subject>Multi-Disciplinary</subject>
		<subject>Engineering</subject>
		<oneline_desc>Present your ideas to the world!</oneline_desc>
		<desc>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[
					"You grow ravenous. You run fevers. You know exhilarations. You can't sleep at night, because your beast-creature ideas want out and turn you in your bed. It is a grand way to live."<br>
						<span style="float:right;">&ndash;Ray Bradbury, <i>Zen in the Art of Writing</i></span><br><br>
						<img onclick="load_image(this); return false;" style="position: relative; display: inline-block; width: 600px; left:50%; margin-left: -300px; cursor: pointer;" src="images/events/bosch_idea_within.png" />
						<br>
				]]>
			</para>
			<para>Are you that kind of an idea-machine? A one man thinktank?</para>
			<para>Are you committed to improve society with your smart solutions and innovative ideas?</para>
			<para>Bosch and Pravega provide you with a platform to wow the world with your ideas!</para>
			<para><![CDATA[<center><b>Lots of exciting prizes and goodies to be won, including an internship at Bosch!</b></center>]]></para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[<b>Theme: Mass transportation</b><br>
					Intelligent Transportation System: Next Novel Solutions<br>]]>
			</para>
			<para>
				Novel technology-based analytical solutions and algorithms that can resolve issues of congestion parking, enhance efficiency of public transportation systems, facilitate dynamic route designs, smarter logistics handling and related challenges.
			</para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[
				<ol style="margin-left:25px;">
					<b>Selected abstracts have been announced!</b>
					<li>
						<i>Radio Frequency Identification (RFID) tags on buses</i><br>
						Karuppasamy Muthiah A<br>
						MNM Jain Engineering College, Chennai<br>
					</li>

					<li>
						<i>Intelligent Traffic Signal System</i><br>
						Subramanian Aravind, Srinivasan Srinikethan<br>
						Amrita College of Engineering, Chennai<br>
					</li>

					<li>
						<i>Au courant Parking System</i><br>
						S.Yadukrishnan and Sourabh Sirdesai<br>
						Aurora's Engineering College, Hyderabad<br>
					</li>
				</ol>
				]]>
			</para>
		</desc>
		<image>porp.png</image>
		<rules_list>
			<rule>Participation as individuals or as teams of two.</rule>
			<rule>Idea presented must be original. Any instances of plagiarism will lead to disqualification.</rule>
			<rule>The contest is open to all undergraduates and postgraduates.</rule>
			<rule>The decision of judges is final and binding.</rule>
			<rule>Selected teams will have to present their papers at Pravega 2014.</rule>
			<rule>There will be no extension in the deadlines. All papers/abstracts received late will be disqualified.</rule>
			<rule>
				<![CDATA[
					<b>Important Dates:</b>
					<ul style="margin-left:25px;">
						<li>10th January, 2014: Abstract submission</li>
						<li>17th January, 2014: Confirmation of selected papers for presentation</li>
						<li>25th January, 2014: Full paper submission.</li>
					</ul>
				]]>
			</rule>
			<rule>
			<![CDATA[
				<ol style="margin-left:25px;">
					<b>Selected abstracts have been announced:</b>
					<li>
						<i>Radio Frequency Identification (RFID) tags on buses</i><br>
						Karuppasamy Muthiah A<br>
						MNM Jain Engineering College, Chennai<br>
					</li>

					<li>
						<i>Intelligent Traffic Signal System</i><br>
						Subramanian Aravind, Srinivasan Srinikethan<br>
						Amrita College of Engineering, Chennai<br>
					</li>

					<li>
						<i>Au courant Parking System</i><br>
						S.Yadukrishnan and Sourabh Sirdesai<br>
						Aurora's Engineering College, Hyderabad<br>
					</li>
				</ol>
				]]>
			</rule>
		</rules_list>
	</event>
	
	<event>
		<name>Idea Within: Energy</name>
		<file_name>iw_energy</file_name>
		<subject>Multi-Disciplinary</subject>
		<subject>Engineering</subject>
		<oneline_desc>Present your ideas to the world!</oneline_desc>
		<desc>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[
					"You grow ravenous. You run fevers. You know exhilarations. You can't sleep at night, because your beast-creature ideas want out and turn you in your bed. It is a grand way to live."<br>
						<span style="float:right;">&ndash;Ray Bradbury, <i>Zen in the Art of Writing</i></span><br><br>
						<img onclick="load_image(this); return false;" style="position: relative; display: inline-block; width: 600px; left:50%; margin-left: -300px; cursor: pointer;" src="images/events/bosch_idea_within.png" />
						<br>
				]]>
			</para>
			<para>Are you that kind of an idea-machine? A one man thinktank?</para>
			<para>Are you committed to improve society with your smart solutions and innovative ideas?</para>
			<para>Bosch and Pravega provide you with a platform to wow the world with your ideas!</para>
			<para><![CDATA[<center><b>Lots of exciting prizes and goodies to be won, including an internship at Bosch!</b></center>]]></para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[<b>Theme: Energy</b><br>
					Smart Grid Design Architecture for Distribution<br>]]>
			</para>
			<para>
				Efficient and affordable technology-based solutions and algorithms for better energy distribution for seamless electric supply to consumption units.
			</para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[
					<ol style="margin-left:25px;">
					<b>Selected abstracts have been announced:</b>
						<li>
							<i>Every Speed Breaker is now a source of power</i><br>
							by M. Narasimha Rushikesh and N. V. Suneel Kumar Reddy<br>
							from K L University, Vijaywada<br>
						</li>

						<li>
							<i>Modelling of Smart Grid and Anti-Theft Controller of ZIGBEE</i><br>
							by Vishnu Chaitanyam and Aravind Murugavel<br>
							from KS Rangasamy College, Erode<br>
						</li>

						<li>
							<i>Optimal Utilization of Grid-tied Solar Power in domestic system</i><br>
							by Dharma Teja Paladugu and Dinesh Narayan<br>
							from Amritha University, Coimbatore<br>
						</li>

						<li>
							<i>Solar LPG Hybrid stove</i><br>
							by G S Abhishek and Chiranth N<br>
							from PESIT, Bangalore<br>
						</li>
					</ol>
				]]>
			</para>
		</desc>
		<image>porp.png</image>
		<rules_list>
			<rule>Participation as individuals or as teams of two.</rule>
			<rule>Idea presented must be original. Any instances of plagiarism will lead to disqualification.</rule>
			<rule>The contest is open to all undergraduates and postgraduates.</rule>
			<rule>The decision of judges is final and binding.</rule>
			<rule>Selected teams will have to present their papers at Pravega 2014.</rule>
			<rule>There will be no extension in the deadlines. All papers/abstracts received late will be disqualified.</rule>
			<rule>
				<![CDATA[
					<b>Important Dates:</b>
					<ul style="margin-left:25px;">
						<li>10th January, 2014: Abstract submission</li>
						<li>17th January, 2014: Confirmation of selected papers for presentation</li>
						<li>25th January, 2014: Full paper submission.</li>
					</ul>
				]]>
			</rule>
			<rule>
			<![CDATA[
				All abstracts are to be mailed to <a href="mailto:janhavi@pravega.org">janhavi@pravega.org</a>
				]]>
			</rule>
		</rules_list>
	</event>
	
		<event>
		<name>Easter Egg Hunt</name>
		<file_name>easter_egg_hunt</file_name>
		<subject>Engineering</subject>
		<subject>Cultural</subject>
		<oneline_desc>Find the hidden easter eggs right here on the Pravega website!</oneline_desc>
		<desc>
			<para>Pravega has scattered seven carefully crafted easter eggs on its website!</para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[
					For instance, type "pravega" while on the Pravega homepage and see what happens ;) 
				]]>
			</para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[
					(Don't know what an easter egg is? <a target="_blank" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Easter_egg_(media)">Check Easter Egg(media) on Wikipedia</a>)
				]]>
			</para>
			<para>You now know one egg, six more are left!</para>
			<para>Trawl through source code, keep an eye out for the fishy and unravel the other easter eggs before January 20th, 2014!</para>	
			<para>
				<![CDATA[
					<center>
					<b>Winners Announced!</b><br>
					Winners: Vamsi Krishna Patchava<br>
					Runner-up: Pushkar Mundada<br>
					Winners will be emailed with prize details soon.
					</center>
				]]>
			</para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[ <CENTER> <b> The competition is over, thank you for participating! Winners will be announced shortly.</b></CENTER>]]>
			</para>	
			<para>
				<![CDATA[ <CENTER> <b> Co-ordinator: </b> <br>Milind Hegde<br> <a href="mailto:milind@pravega.org" target="_blank">milind@pravega.org</a></CENTER>]]>
			</para>	
		</desc>
		<image></image>
		<rules_list>
			<rule>The competition is open to school, undergraduate and post graduate students.</rule>
			<rule>There are 7 easter eggs on the website, of which one is known (see descriptions tab).</rule>
			<rule>When you're done or have uncovered all 7 easter eggs (or both!), immediately shoot an email to <![CDATA[<a href="mailto:milind@pravega.org">milind@pravega.org</a>]]> describing the eggs and how you found them.</rule>
			<rule>The winner will be decided based on number of eggs recovered and time taken. So don't dally!</rule>
			<rule>Team size is 2. (Individual participation is also allowed)</rule>
			<rule>Cross-college teams are allowed.</rule>
			<rule>Prizes will be awarded only after verification of the participants' identities.</rule>
			<rule>Last date for entries is January 20th, 2014.</rule>
			<rule>You must register for the event on the Pravega website before your entries via email are considered valid.</rule>
		</rules_list> 
	</event>
	
	
	<event>
		<name>Tech-O-Rama</name>
		<file_name>online_quiz</file_name>
		<subject>Quizzes</subject>
		<oneline_desc>Online Tech Quiz</oneline_desc>
		<desc>
			<para><![CDATA[<center><b><a href="https://www.facebook.com/PravegaIISc/posts/428382253956571" target="_blank">The contest is over and the winners are out! Congratultions!</a></b></center>]]></para>
			<para>Do your friends rush to you for tech-support? Does your presence make salespersons feel uneasy? Are you a regular prowler on the open source forums?</para>
			<para>Pravega calls all digital natives for a fun-filled online technology quiz on the 21st of December! 10K worth of prizes + goodies at stake!</para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[
				<center>Date: 21st December, 2013<br>
				Time: 9:00PM-9:40PM (40 minutes)</center>]]>
			</para>
			<para>
				Please register on <![CDATA[<a href="http://www.dare2compete.com/competitions/9633/IISc-Pravega-Tech-O-Rama/Indian-Institute-Science-Bangalore" target="_blank">dare2compete.com</a>]]> for the quiz.  
				You also need to be registered here on Pravega.org to be eligible to win prizes
			</para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[
				<b>Prizes</b><br>

				1st Prize: Rs. 5000<br>
				2nd Prize: Rs. 3000<br>
				3rd Prize: Rs. 2000<br>
				Certificates from IISc Pravega and Goodies for top 10 teams.]]>
			</para>
		</desc>
		<image>porp.png</image>
		<rules_list>
			<rule>Two people per team. Cross-college participation is allowed.</rule>
			<rule>Participation is open to all.</rule>
			<rule>The quiz will be hosted on 21st December, 2013 from 9:00-9:40PM.</rule>
			<rule>There will be 25 questions to be answered in 40 minutes.</rule>
			<rule>There will be no audio/video questions.</rule>
			<rule>Prizes will be awarded after verification of college ID cards of both team members.</rule>
			<rule>No person can be a member of more than one team.</rule>
		</rules_list>
	</event>
	
	<event>
		<name>Alphabet Soup</name>
		<file_name>online_general_quiz</file_name>
		<subject>Quizzes</subject>
		<oneline_desc>A mixed bag of 26 questions online, on 18th January</oneline_desc>
		<desc>
			<para>Pravega calls all quiz aficionados for a bout of fun-filled online quizzing on Saturday, 18th of January, 2014.</para>
			<para>26 Questions - each alphabet will have representation in one answer.</para>
			<para>10K worth of prizes + goodies at stake!</para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[
				<center><b>Date:</b> 18th January, 2014<br>
				<b>Time:</b> 9:00PM-9:40PM (40 minutes)</center>]]>
			</para>
			<para>
				Please register on <![CDATA[<a href="http://www.dare2compete.com/" target="_blank">dare2compete.com</a>]]> for the quiz.  
				You also need to be registered here on Pravega.org to be eligible to win prizes.
			</para>
			<para>
				<![CDATA[
				<b>Prizes</b><br>

				1st Prize: Rs. 5000<br>
				2nd Prize: Rs. 3000<br>
				3rd Prize: Rs. 2000<br>
				Certificates from IISc Pravega and Goodies for top 10 teams.]]>
			</para>
		</desc>
		<image>porp.png</image>
		<rules_list>
			<rule>Two people per team. Cross-college participation is allowed.</rule>
			<rule>Participation is open to all.</rule>
			<rule>The quiz will be hosted on 18th January, 2014 from 9:00-9:40PM.</rule>
			<rule>There will be 26 questions to be answered in 40 minutes.</rule>
			<rule>There will be no audio/video questions.</rule>
			<rule>Prizes will be awarded after verification of college ID cards of both team members.</rule>
			<rule>No person can be a member of more than one team.</rule>
		</rules_list>
	</event>
	
	<event>
		<name>Inquizitive</name>
		<file_name>inquizitive</file_name>
		<subject>Quizzes</subject>
		<oneline_desc>Pravega's biggest quizzing event - presented by IDBI Bank at the JN Tata Auditorium</oneline_desc>
		<desc>
			<para>Time to put on your thinking hats!</para>
			<para>Pravega in association with IDBI Bank presents Inquizitive <![CDATA[&mdash;]]> a quiz for pre-university and college students.</para>
			<para>Bangalore's crazy quiz-community served with Pravega's bamboozling questions<![CDATA[&mdash;]]>and Rs. 25,000 in prizes<![CDATA[&mdash;]]> creates the perfect recipe for one cracker of a quiz! </para>
			<para>Our promise: Inquizitive's googlies and benders will leave you oohing and aahing and facepalming.</para>
			<para>The Quiz, to be hosted by the charismatic Mr. Llyod Sandhana of Greycaps, will be held at the prestigious JN Tata auditorium. </para>
			<para>Inquizitive is one of the biggest highlights of Pravega. Don't miss it.</para>
		</desc>
		<image>porp.png</image>
		<rules_list>
			<rule>Inquizitive will begin at 9 am on Sunday, February 2nd.</rule>
			<rule>Teams of 2 members each. Cross-college teams are allowed.</rule>
			<rule>6 teams will make it to the finals.</rule>
		</rules_list>
	</event>
	
	<event>
		<name>Science Quizine</name>
		<file_name>science_quizine</file_name>
		<subject>Quizzes</subject>
		<oneline_desc>Pravega's Mega Science Quiz</oneline_desc>
		<desc>
			<para>Over the course of a century, the hallowed portals of IISc have played host to India's greatest scientists - Sir C.V. Raman, Satish Dhawan, Homi Bhabha, Vikram Sarabhai,<![CDATA[ &hellip;]]></para>
			<para>Science in India and IISc - they are inseparably intertwined together.</para>
			<para>Can there really be a better venue than IISc to host a mega science and technology quiz?</para>
			<para>Jam packed with interesting questions, this event guarantees to be a thriller! Prize money of Rs. 15,000 is up for grabs!</para>
		</desc>
		<image>porp.png</image>
		<rules_list>
			<rule>Science Quizine will be begin at 9:30am on Saturday, February 1st.</rule>
			<rule>Teams of 3 participants each. Cross-college teams are allowed.</rule>
			<rule>6 teams will make it to the finals.</rule>
		</rules_list>
	</event>
	
</event_data>